漫威影业
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供学习  禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻译     草草
校对     草草
时间轴    吉吉家的安斯斯
时间轴    安斯斯家的吉吉
后期     吉吉
自我上次在这里见大家过去好一阵了
Been a while since I was up here in front of you.
我这次还是帮大家个忙  照稿读吧
Maybe I'll do us all a favor and just stick to the cards.
有人猜测
There's been speculation
我卷入了之前发生在
that I was involved in the events that occurred
高速和屋顶上的事件
on the freeway and the rooftop...
抱歉  斯塔克先生
I'm sorry, Mr Stark,
你真的指望我们相信
but do you honestly expect us to believe that
那是一个穿战衣的保镖  碰巧出现
that was a bodyguard in a suit that conveniently appeared,
尽管你特别讨厌用保镖
despite the fact that you sorely despise bodyguards?
是的
Yes.
而且这位神秘保镖还不知怎么配备了
And this mysterious bodyguard was somehow equipped
未公开的斯托克高科技动力战斗...
with an undisclosed Stark high-tech powered battle...
莫斯科
我知道情况让人糊涂
I know that it's confusing.
质疑官方说辞是一回事
It is one thing to question the official story,
但提出疯狂指控  或暗示说
and another thing entirely to make wild accusations,
我是个超级英雄可是另一码事了
or insinuate that I'm a superhero.
承认吧  我不是做英雄的料
I mean, let's face it, I'm not the heroic type.
我有一堆性格缺陷
A laundry list of character defects,
犯过那么多错误  还很公开
all the mistakes I've made, largely public.
事实就是
The truth is
我就是钢铁侠
I am Iron Man.
伊凡
Ivan.
万尼亚
Vanya.
那本该是你的
别去听那些垃圾
对不起
我能给你的  只有我的知识
斯塔克
方舟反应堆
安东·万科  霍华德·斯塔克
托尼是钢铁侠
斯塔克的方舟
托尼·斯塔克  "我是钢铁侠"
时代杂志  钢铁侠
钢铁侠稳定了东西方关系
钢铁侠2
方向270  速度30节
270 at 30 knots.
保持在1.5万英尺上
Holding steady at 15,000 feet.
可以从空投点撤出
You are clear for exfiltration over the drop zone.
六个月后
纽约  法拉盛  斯塔克博览会
斯塔克博览会
回来的感觉真好
It's good to be back.
-想我了吗  -炸点什么
- You missed me? - Blow something up!
我也想你们了  炸点东西
I missed you, too. Blow something up?
我已经炸过了
I already did that.
我不是说  这世界因为我
I'm not saying that the world is enjoying its
而迎来了最长的一段持续和平时期
longest period of uninterrupted peace in years because of me.
我不是说
I'm not saying
从囚禁的灰烬里
that from the ashes of captivity,
涅槃了人类史上最伟大的
never has a greater phoenix metaphor
成真的隐喻凤凰
been personified in human history.
我不是说
I'm not saying
山姆大叔可以安详地躺在草坪躺椅上
that Uncle Sam can kick back on a lawn chair,
喝一杯冰茶
sipping on an iced tea
因为我还没遇见哪个有种跟
because I haven't come across anyone who's man enough
状态最佳的我硬碰硬的家伙
to go toe-to-toe with me on my best day.
我爱你  托尼
I love you, Tony!
拜托  这不是关于我
Please, it's not about me.
也不是关于你
It's not about you.
甚至不是关于我们  而是关于遗产
It's not even about us. It's about legacy.
是关于我们决定要为后世子孙留下什么
It's about what we choose to leave behind for future generations.
所以  在接下来一年里
And that's why for the next year
也是自1974年起第一次
and for the first time since 1974,
全世界各国家各企业
the best and brightest men and women
最聪明最棒的男男女女
of nations and corporations the world over
将整合资源  分享共同愿景
will pool their resources, share their collective vision,
从而留下一个更美好的未来
to leave behind a brighter future.
重点不是我们
It's not about us.
所以  我是要说
Therefore, what I'm saying,
如果我有任何话想说的话
if I'm saying anything,
就是欢迎再次来到斯塔克博览会
is welcome back to the Stark Expo.
现在  一位特别出场嘉宾
And now, making a special guest appearance
将跨越生死之隔  来向你说明一切的
from the great beyond to tell you what it's all about,
有请我父亲  霍华德
please welcome my father, Howard.
科技可以实现一切
Everything is achievable through technology.
更好的生活  强健的体魄
Better living, robust health,
以及人类史上第一次
and for the first time in human history,
世界和平的可能性
the possibility of world peace.
所以  代表斯塔克工业全体
So, from all of us here at Stark Industries,
我要亲自向你介绍
I would like to personally introduce you to
未来之城
the City of the Future.
科技为人类带来了无限可能
Technology holds infinite possibilities for mankind,
血毒素含量: 19%
终有一日  将摒除社会的一切问题
and will one day rid society of all its ills.
很快  科技将影响
Soon, technology will affect
你日常生活的方式
the way you live your life every day.
再不用做无聊的工作
No more tedious work,
让你有更多时间做闲适的活动
leaving more time for leisure activities
享受美好的生活
and enjoying the sweet life.
斯塔克博览会  欢迎您
The Stark Expo. Welcome.
我们在斯塔克博览会的开幕式现场为您直播
We are coming to you live from the kickoff of the Stark Expo,
斯塔克博览会开幕仪式
托尼·斯塔克发表主题演讲
托尼·斯塔克刚刚走下了主舞台
where Tony Stark has just walked off stage.
如果你今晚无法到场也没关系
Don't worry if you can't make it down here tonight
因为博览会是全年开放的
because this Expo goes on all year long.
我也会在这里游览各个景点
And I'm gonna be here checking out all the attractions
展馆  以及来自世界各地的发明
and the pavilions and the inventions from all around the world.
-务必跟我一起  -好了
- Make sure you join me... - All right,
外面乱成一团  小心
it's a zoo out there, watch out.
开门  走
Open up, let's go.
见到你们很高兴
Nice to see you.
好  谢谢
All right. Thank you.
-我记得你  -托尼
- I remember you. - Tony, Tony...
打给我
Call me.
行了  走吧
Come on, come on.
你好  很荣幸
Hello. It would be a pleasure.
-好了  -回见  伙计
- Okay. - See you, buddy.
这是拉里
This is Larry.
甲骨文的当家  真荣幸
Hey, the oracle of Oracle. What a pleasure.
拉里·埃利森本尊
-见到你真高兴  -打给我哦
- Nice to see you. - Call me. Call me.
-拉里·金  -拉里
- Larry King. - Larry!
太好了  我的朋友们
Yes, my people, my people.
走吧  托尼  我们走
Come on, Tony. There we go.
-很顺利  -还不算糟
- Very mellow. - That wasn't so bad.
是啊  完美
No, it was perfect.
看看这是什么  新款车
Look what we got here, the new model.
-她是随车附赠的吗  -希望是的
- Does she come with the car? - I certainly hope so.
-你是  -玛西尔[法警]
- And you are? - Marshal.
爱尔兰名字
Irish.
-我喜欢  -认识你很高兴  托尼
- I like it. - Pleased to meet you, Tony.
我开  行吗
I'm on the wheel. Do you mind?
你是哪里人
Where you from?
-贝德福德  -你来这里干什么
- Bedford. - What are you doing here?
-找你  -是吗  你找到我了
- Looking for you. - Yeah? You found me.
-你待会儿有什么事吗  -送传票
- What are you up to later? - Serving subpoenas.
他不喜欢被人递东西
He doesn't like to be handed things.
-是啊  我的怪癖  -我拿着就行
- Yeah, I have a peeve. - I got it.
你必须于
You are hereby ordered
明早9点出席参议院
to appear before the Senate Armed Services Committee
军事委员会的听证会
tomorrow morning at 9:00 a.m.
-能出示下证件吗  -你想看我的证件
- Can I see a badge? - You wanna see the badge?
他喜欢证件
He likes the badge.
-现在还喜欢吗  -嗯
- You still like it? - Yep.
我们离华府多远
How far are we from D.C.?
华府吗  250英里
D.C.? 250 miles.
华盛顿特区
斯塔克先生  我们可以
Mr. Stark, could we
继续之前的话题了吗
pick up now where we left off?
斯塔克先生  请注意
Mr. Stark. Please.
-什么事  亲爱的  -可以认真听吗
- Yes, dear? - Can I have your attention?
当然
Absolutely.
你是否持有一件特制武器
Do you or do you not possess a specialized weapon?
-我没有  -你没有吗
- I do not. - You do not?
参议院军事委员会  武器化战衣国防项目听证会
我没有  这要看你怎么定义"武器"一词了
I do not. Well, it depends on how you define the word "weapon."
-钢铁侠武器  -我的装置不符合这一描述
- The Iron Man weapon. - My device does not fit that description.
那你会怎么描述它
Well... How would you describe it?
我对它的描述就是它的准确定义  参议员
I would describe it by defining it as what it is, Senator.
参议院军事委员会  武器化战衣国防项目听证会
-是什么  -高科技假肢
- As? - It's a high-tech prosthesis.
那是...
That is... That is...
那才是我认为最合适的描述
That's actually the most apt description I can make of it.
它是件武器  斯塔克先生
It's a weapon. It's a weapon, Mr. Stark.
拜托  如果你的优先考虑
Please, if your priority
真是美国公民的幸福
was actually the well-being of the American citizen...
我的优先考虑是将钢铁侠武器交给
My priority is to get the iron Man weapon turned over to the
美国人民
people of the United States of America.
那你别想了
Well, you can forget it.
托尼·斯塔克
斯塔克工业执行总裁
我就是钢铁侠  我和战衣是一体的
I am Iron Man. The suit and I are one.
上交钢铁侠战衣就是交出我自己
To turn over the Iron Man suit would be to turn over myself,
这相当于卖身或卖淫
which is tantamount to indentured servitude or prostitution,
这要看你是哪个州的了
depending on what state you're in.
你别想拿到它
You can't have it.
听着  我不是专家
Look, I'm no expert...
在卖淫方面吗  当然不是
In prostitution? Of course not.
你可是参议员  拜托
You're a senator. Come on.
我不是武器专家
I'm no expert in weapons.
我们请来了一位武器专家
We have somebody here who is an expert on weapons.
斯特恩参议员
宾夕法尼亚  军事委员会主席
我现在传召贾斯汀·汉默
I'd now like to call Justin Hammer,
我们现在的主武器承包商
our current primary weapons contractor.
贾斯汀·汉默
汉默工业执行总裁
国防部主系统承包商
请记录显示我看到了
Let the record reflect that I observed
汉默先生走进会场
Mr. Hammer entering the chamber,
而我在想
and I am wondering
还会不会有真正的专家出席
if and when any actual expert will also be in attendance.
贾斯汀·汉默
汉默工业执行总裁
国防部主系统承包商
当然了
Absolutely.
我不是专家  我得听你的  安托尼
I'm no expert. I defer to you, Anthony.
你才是金童嘛
You're the wonder boy.
参议员  可以吗
Senator, if I may.
我或许不是专家  但知道谁是最大的专家吗
I may well not be an expert, but you know who was the expert?
你爸爸  霍华德·斯塔克
Your dad. Howard Stark.
他是我们所有人的父亲
Really a father to us all,
也是军事工业时代之父
and to the military-industrial age.
我们说清楚  他可不是嬉皮士
Let's just be clear. He was no flower child.
而是一只雄狮
He was a lion.
我们都清楚本次听证会的原因
We all know why we're here.
过去六个月里
In the last six months,
安托尼·斯塔克创造了一把有无限可能的利剑
Anthony Stark has created a sword with untold possibilities.
但他却坚称那是块盾牌
And yet he insists it's a shield.
贾斯汀·汉默
汉默工业执行总裁
国防部主系统承包商
他叫我们躲在它后面  信任他
He asks us to trust him as we cower behind it.
真希望这让我感到安心  安托尼  真的
I wish I were comforted, Anthony, I really do.
我希望离家时能不用锁门
I'd love to leave my door unlocked when I leave the house,
但这里不是加拿大
but this ain't Canada.
我们生活在充满重大威胁的世界里
You know, we live in a world of grave threats,
这些威胁  斯塔克先生并不总能预料到
threats that Mr. Stark will not always be able to foresee.
谢谢
Thank you.
上帝保佑钢铁侠  上帝保佑美国
God bless Iron Man. God bless America.
说得很好  汉默先生
That is well said, Mr. Hammer.
委员会现在要请
The committee would now like to invite
詹姆斯·罗德中校进入会场
Lieutenant Colonel James Rhodes to the chamber.
罗德  什么
Rhodey? What?
哥们  没想到会在这里见到你
Hey, buddy. I didn't expect to see you here.
是我  我来了  认了吧  向前看
Look, it's me, I'm here. Deal with it. Let's move on.
我就是...
I just...
-省省  -好吧  我不说了
- Drop it. - All right, I'll drop it.
我面前有一份完整的钢铁侠武器报告
I have before me a complete report on the Iron Man weapon,
参议院军事委员会  武器化战衣国防项目听证会
由罗德中校整理  中校  作为记录
compiled by Colonel Rhodes. And, Colonel, for the record,
请读一下第57页第四段
can you please read page 57, paragraph four?
您是要我从我的报告中
You're requesting that I read specific selections
-选读一段吗  参议员  -是的
- from my report, Senator? - Yes, sir.
我以为我要以更全面细致的方式
It was my understanding that I was going to be testifying
进行作证
in a much more comprehensive and detailed manner.
我知道  今天很多事都发生了变化
I understand. A lot of things have changed today.
-麻烦你读一下  -你知道
- So if you could just read... - You do understand
如果脱离上下文  只读一段  是不能体现
that reading a single paragraph out of context does not reflect
-我最终的总结...  -读吧  中校
- the summary of my final... - Just read it, Colonel.
我知道  谢谢
I do. Thank you.
好吧
Very well.
詹姆斯·罗德中校  美国空军武器采购联络人
"因为他的行动
"As he does not operate
不明确受任何政府机构管辖
within any definable branch of government,
钢铁侠对于国家
Iron Man presents a potential threat
和其利益都构成
to the security of both the nation
潜在威胁"
and to her interests."
但我之后还总结了
I did, however, go on to summarize
钢铁侠存在的好处大于弊端
that the benefits of Iron Man far outweigh the liabilities.
对我们有利的作法是...
And that it would be in our interest...
够了  中校
That's enough, Colonel.
参议院军事委员会  武器化战衣国防项目听证会
-让斯塔克先生  -够了
- to fold Mr. Stark... - That's enough.
加入现有的指挥链  参议员
into the existing chain of command, Senator.
我不喜欢团队合作
I'm not a joiner,
但如果你客气点  我愿考虑国防部长
but I'll consider Secretary of Defense, if you ask nice.
我们可以商量下工作时间
We can amend the hours a little bit.
如果可以  我还想展示
I'd like to go on and show, if I may,
与你的报告相关的图像
the imagery that's connected to your report.
我认为现在就向公众展示这些画面
I believe it is somewhat premature to reveal these images
-可能还为时尚早  -恕我直言
- to the general public at this time. - With all due respect,
中校  我懂
Colonel, I understand.
麻烦你为我们讲解一下
And if you could just narrate those for us,
我们会很感激的
we'd be very grateful.
请调出图像
Let's have the images.
参议院军事委员会  武器化战衣国防项目听证会
根据情报显示  这些图片中的装置
Intelligence suggests that the devices seen in these photos
正是在尝试复制有人驾驭的
are, in fact, attempts at making manned copies
斯塔克先生的战衣
of Mr. Stark's suit.
情报得到了
This has been corroborated
我们盟友和当地情报部门的佐证
by our allies and local intelligence on the ground,
情报还显示  这些战衣很可能
indicating that these suits are quite possibly,
已经可以运行了
at this moment, operational.
等一下  哥们  我看看
Hold on one second, buddy. Let me see something here.
天呐  我真厉害  我征用了你的屏幕
Boy, I'm good. I commandeered your screens.
我需要它们  该公开公开了
I need them. Time for a little transparency.
欢迎  斯塔克先生
参议院军事委员会  武器化战衣国防项目听证会
我们看看真实情况如何吧
Now, let's see what's really going on.
他在干什么
What is he doing?
麻烦大家看着屏幕
If you will direct your attention to said screens...
那里应该是朝鲜
I believe that's North Korea.
可以关掉它吗  把它关掉
Can you turn that off? Take it off.
伊朗
Iran.
并没有急迫的大威胁吧
No grave immediate threat here.
那是贾斯汀·汉默吗
Is that Justin Hammer?
汉默怎么也做起这个了
How did Hammer get in the game?
贾斯汀  你上电视了  看啊
Justin, you're on TV. Focus up.
好  左转
Okay, give me a left twist.
左转没问题  再右转
Left's good. Turn to the right.
该死  该死
Oh, Shit. Oh, Shit!
参议院军事委员会  武器化战衣国防项目听证会
斯特恩参议员
宾夕法尼亚  军事委员会主席
我认为大部分国家还要再研究个五年十年的
Yeah, I'd say most countries, five, 10 years away.
汉默工业  20年
Hammer Industries, 20.
我想说明  那台测试机没有损毁
I'd like to point out that that test pilot survived.
参议院军事委员会  武器化战衣国防项目听证会
行了  重点是  他在制造这个
I think we're done, is the point that he's making.
我觉得没必要...
I don't think there's any reason...
重点是  不用谢...
The point is, you're welcome,
-吧  -谢什么
- I guess. - For what?
因为我是你的核威慑
Because I'm your nuclear deterrent.
很有效  我们安全了  美国安全了
It's working. We're safe. America is secure.
你要我的东西  你别想拿到
You want my property? You can't have it.
但我帮了你个忙
But I did you a big favor.
我已经成功民营世界和平了
I've successfully privatized world peace.
你还要什么啊  暂时是无忧了
What more do you want? For now!
我也想配合这些小丑
I tried to play ball with these ass-clowns.
参议院军事委员会  武器化战衣国防项目听证会
去你妈  斯塔克先生  去你妈的
Fuck you, Mr. Stark... Fuck you, buddy.
休会  今天休会
We're adjourned. We're adjourned for today.
-好  -你真是讨喜
- Okay. - You've been a delight.
我是人民的人
My bond is with the people.
我会为了自己乐意为这个国家效劳
And I will serve this great nation at the pleasure of myself.
我已经证实了一件事
If there's one thing I've proven
那就是  我是最会自己找乐子的人
it's that you can count on me to pleasure myself.
加州  马里布
醒醒  爸爸回家了
Wake up. Daddy's home.
欢迎回家  先生
Welcome home, sir.
恭喜您开幕仪式大获成功
Congratulations on the opening ceremonies. They were such a success,
参议院听证会也是
as was your Senate hearing.
而且容我说  终于能看到
And may I say how refreshing it is
您穿着衣服的视频真是令人耳目一新  先生
to finally see you in a video with your clothing on, sir.
你
You!
我发誓  我要拆了你  泡了你的主板
I swear to God I'll dismantle you. I'll soak your motherboard.
把你改造成酒架
I'll turn you into a wine rack.
这恶心玩意我一天要喝多少盎司
How many ounces a day of this gobbledegook am I supposed to drink?
为抑制症状  每日摄入量已上涨到80盎司
We are up to 80 ounces a day to counteract the symptoms, sir.
检查钯含量
Check palladium levels.
血毒素含量  24%
Blood toxicity, 24%.
看来持续使用钢铁侠战衣
It appears that the continued use of the Iron Man suit
加重了您的病情
is accelerating your condition.
又一个能源核耗尽了
Another core has been depleted.
老天  耗得真快
God, they're running out quick.
我已经对所有已知元素进行了模拟计算
I have run simulations on every known element,
但没有一个可以作为钯核的可用替换
and none can serve as a viable replacement for the palladium core.
您的时间和选择都不多了
You are running out of both time and options.
很遗憾  维系您生命的装置
Unfortunately, the device that's keeping you alive
也在杀死你
is also killing you.
波茨小姐靠近了
Miss Potts is approaching.
-我建议您告诉她  -静音
- I recommend that you inform her... - Mute.
这是个玩笑吗
Is this a joke?
-你怎么想的  -什么
- What are you thinking? - What?
-你怎么想的  -我想我挺忙的
- What are you thinking? - Hey, I'm thinking I'm busy.
而你在生什么事的气
And you're angry about something.
你鼻伤风了吗  我不想染上病
Do you have the sniffles? I don't wanna get sick.
-你是刚捐了...  -有事说吧
- Did you just donate... - Keep your business.
我们所有的现代艺术藏品给
our entire modern art collection to the...
-美国童军  -美国童军
- Boy Scouts of America. - Boy Scouts of America?
是的  这个组织非常有价值
Yes. It is a worthwhile organization.
我并没亲自去查箱子  但差不多吧
I didn't physically check the crates but, basically, yes.
而且不是"我们的"藏品
And it's not "our" collection,
是我的藏品  别见怪
it's my collection. No offense.
不  你知道吗
No, you know what?
我觉得我有权说"我们的"藏品
I think I'm actually entitled to say "our" collection
因为我花了超过10年的时间
considering the time that I put in, over 10 years,
-整理这些藏品  -可以返税  我需要
- curating that. - It was a tax write-off. I needed that.
我也就有大概8011件事
You know, there's only about 8,011 things
非常需要跟你谈
that I really need to talk to you about.
呆呆  别发呆了
Dummy. Hey, stop spacing out.
那部分布里奇波特已经在做了
The Bridgeport's already machining that part.
博览会完全就是浪费时间
The Expo is a gigantic waste of time.
我需要你戴医用口罩  直到你好起来
I need you to wear a surgical mask until you're feeling better.
-行吗  -好无礼
- Is that okay? - That's rude.
博览会对我来说是最重要的了
There's nothing more important to me than the Expo.
是我最关心的事
It's my primary point of concern.
-不知道你为什么  -博览会是你膨胀的自大
- I don't know why you're... - The Expo is your ego gone crazy.
看啊
Look at that.
这才是现代艺术
That's modern art.
这个要挂起来
That's going up.
-你开玩笑吧  -我这就去挂
- You've got to be kidding. - I'm gonna put this up right now.
-这很重要  -斯塔克工业完全一团乱
- This is vital. - Stark is in complete disarray.
-你明白吗  -不  我们的股价是有史最高
- You understand that? - No. Our stocks have never been higher.
-是啊  从管理层的角度来说  -这不是
- Yes, from a managerial standpoint. - You are missing...
如果乱了
Well, if it's messy,
-那就恢复原样  -我给你举个例子
- then let's double back. - Let me give you an example.
-说别的吧  -不不不
- Let's move on to another subject. - No, no, no, no.
你别想把巴尼特·纽曼的画拿掉
You are not taking down the Barnett Newman
-挂上那个  -我没要把它拿掉
- and hanging that up! - I'm not taking it down.
只是把它换成这个
I'm just replacing it with this.
-我看看的  -好吧  随你
- Let's see what I can get going here. - Okay, fine.
我要说的是  我们已经给风力农场的人
My point is, we have already awarded contracts
-签了合同  -别说"风力农场"
- to the wind farm people. - Yeah. Don't say "Wind farm."
-还有塑料植树  -我本就胀气
- And to the plastic plantation tree, - I'm already feeling gassy.
那可是你的主意  他们已经在拿工资了
which was your idea, by the way. Those people are on payroll...
-全是我的主意  -而你不做决定
- Everything was my idea. - And you won't make a decision.
我已经不在乎自由派的小算盘了
I don't care about the liberal agenda anymore.
无聊  我要给你个无聊预警
It's boring. Boring. I'm giving you a boring alert.
-你来做吧  -我做什么
- You do it. - I do what?
好主意  我才想到  你来管理公司
Excellent idea. I just figured this out. You run the company.
-是啊  -派珀  我需要你
- Yeah, - Pepper, I need you
-我也想管好公司  -管理整个公司
- I'm trying to run the company. - to run the company.
-别想了  直接做吧  -你不肯
- Well, stop trying to do it and do it. - You will not
-我不是叫你去想  -给我我需要的信息
- I'm not asking you to try to do it - give me the information I need
-我叫你真的去做  -来完成工作
- I'm asking you to physically do it. - in order to...
我要你去做
I need you to do it.
-我也想啊  -派珀  你没听懂
- I am trying to do it. - Pepper, you're not listening to me!
-不  是你不懂  -我想让你做执行总裁
- No, you are not listening to me. - I'm trying to make you CEO.
你干吗不让我说
Why won't you let me?
-你喝酒了吗  -喝了叶绿素
- Have you been drinking? - Chlorophyll.
我在此不可撤回地认命你
I hereby irrevocably appoint you
为斯塔克工业的主席和执行总裁
chairman and CEO of Stark Industries,
即刻生效
effective immediately.
说定了
Yeah, done deal.
好吧
Okay?
我其实好好想过了
I've actually given this a fair amount of thought,
信不信由你  还做了猎头
believe it or not. Doing a bit of headhunting, so to speak,
想找到一个配得上的继任者
trying to figure out who a worthy successor would be.
然后我意识到
And then I realized
是你  一直都是你
it's you. It's always been you.
我原以为会有法律问题
I thought there'd be a legal issue,
但其实  我是可以指认继任者的
but actually I'm capable of appointing my successor.
我的继任者就是你
My successor being you.
恭喜了
Congratulations?
-接受吧  -我不知道该怎么想
- Take it, just take it. - I don't know what to think.
别想  喝吧
Don't think. Drink.
好了
There you go.
摩纳哥古董车大奖赛
公证人来了
The notary's here!
你可以来签转交文件吗
Can you please come sign the transfer paperwork?
我在跟哈皮打拳呢
I'm on Happy time.
-抱歉  -那是干什么
- Sorry. - What the hell was that?
这叫综合格斗  刚诞生三周左右
It's called mixed martial arts. It's been around for three weeks.
这叫肮脏拳击  历史悠久了
It's called dirty boxing. There's nothing new about it.
好了  举起来  来吧
All right, put them up. Come on.
我保证这会是唯一一次
I promise you this is the only time
我要你把公司签字转交给我
I will ask you to sign over your company.
请在每一栏写下姓名缩写
I need you to initial each box.
第一课  眼睛永远不要离开...
Lesson one. Never take your eye off...
行了  我打完了
That's it. I'm done.
你叫什么  小姐
What's your name, lady?
拉什曼  娜塔莉·拉什曼
Rushman. Natalie Rushman.
过来  到教堂里来
Front and center. Come into the church.
不  你不会真叫她...
No. You're seriously not gonna ask...
如果庭上愿意的话  他愿意
If it pleases the court, which it does.
-没事的  -抱歉  他很古怪
- It's no problem. - I'm sorry. He's very eccentric.
什么
What?
-你可以教她一课吗  -没问题
- Can you give her a lesson? - No problem.
-派珀  -什么
- Peppet - What?
-她是谁  -法律部的
- Who is she? - She is from legal.
还是昂贵的潜在性骚扰诉讼
And she is potentially a very expensive sexual harassment lawsuit
如果你再那么朝她抛媚眼的话
if you keep ogling her like that.
我需要个新助理  老板
I need a new assistant, boss.
是的  我这里有三位很棒的候选人
Yes, and I've got three excellent potential candidates.
他们都准备好见你了
They're lined up and ready to meet you.
我没时间见他们
I don't have time to meet.
我马上需要个人  就她了
I need someone now. I feel like it's her.
不行
No, it's not.
-你打过拳击吗  -是的
- You ever boxed before? - I have, yes.
跆搏  美臀训练营
What, like, the Tae Bo? Booty Boot Camp?
塑身操那种的吗
Crunch? Something like that?
-你的名字怎么拼  娜塔莉  -拉什曼
- How do I spell your name, Natalie? - R-U-S-H-M-A-N.
怎么  你还要谷歌她吗
What, are you gonna google her now?
不是说我朝她抛媚眼吗
I thought I was ogling her.
她还真是厉害
Very, very impressive individual.
-你真是死性不改  知道吗  -她精通
- You're so predictable, you know that? - She's fluent in
法语  意大利语  俄语和拉丁语
French, Italian, Russian, Latin.
-谁会说拉丁语啊  -没有人
- Who speaks Latin? - No one speaks Latin.
-没有吗  -那是死语言
- No one speaks Latin? - It's a dead language.
可以读写拉丁语
You can read Latin or you can write Latin,
-但不能说的  -你在东京做过模特吗
- but you can't speak Latin... - Did you model in Tokyo?
-她可是在东京做过模特  -好吧
- 'Cause she modeled in Tokyo. - Well...
我需要她  她有我需要的一切
I need her. She's got everything that I need.
第一规则  眼睛永远不要离开对手
Rule number one, never take your eye off your opponent.
天呐
Oh, my God!
-哈皮  -这才像话
- Happy! - That's what I'm talking about.
-我滑倒了  -是吗
- I just slipped. - You did?
-嗯  -我看像是被击倒了哦
- Yeah. - Looks like a TKO to me.
我需要你的指纹[印象]
Just... I need your impression.
你沉默寡言  或许是那种灵魂老的人
You have a quiet reserve. I don't know, you have an old soul.
-我是说指纹  -好吧
- I meant your fingerprint. - Right.
-怎么样了  -很好  这就完成
- So, how are we doing? - Great. Just wrapping up.
你是老板了
You're the boss.
没有别的事了吧  斯塔克先生
Will that be all, Mr. Stark?
-还有  -没了  就这样了  拉什曼小姐
- No. - Yes, that will be all, Ms. Rushman.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
-我想要一个  -不行
- I want one. - No.
摩纳哥
摩纳哥古董车大奖赛
这里是欧洲  不管接下来20分钟里发生什么
You know, it's Europe. Whatever happens the next 20 minutes,
-都顺其自然吧  -顺其自然
- just go with it. - Go with it?
-什么意思  -比如那个  -斯塔克先生
- Go with what? - Like that. - Mr. Stark?
你好  您的旅程如何
Hello. How was your flight?
非常好  见到你真高兴
It was excellent. Boy, it's nice to see you.
如果您不介意
We have one photographer
有位摩纳哥汽车俱乐部的摄影师想给您拍照
from the ACM, if you don't mind. Okay?
-什么时候发生的  -什么
- When did this happen? - What?
-什么时候  -是你逼我的
- When? - You made me do it.
-我怎么逼你了  -你辞职了
- I made you do what? - You quit.
笑一个  看那里
Smile. Look right there.
别一副便秘的表情了
Stop acting constipated.
-别把鼻孔吹大了  -死性不改
- Don't flare your nostrils. - You are so predictable.
-真是不可思议  -这边来
- That's the amazing thing. - Right this way.
谢谢
Thanks.
-你太美了  -谢谢您
- You look fantastic. - Why, thank you very much.
这不太专业  有什么日程
But that's unprofessional. What's on the docket?
9:30有一场晚餐
You have a 9:30 dinner.
完美  我11点到
Perfect. I'll be there at 11:00.
-我们坐这里吗  -当然
- Is this us? - Absolutely.
可以坐这里
It can be.
-太好了  就这里了  -好
- Great. Make it us. - Okay.
-马斯克先生  你好吗  -派珀
- Mr. Musk. How are you? - Hi, Pepper.
伊隆·马斯克本尊
-恭喜你升职  -非常感谢
- Congratulations on the promotion. - Thank you very much.
伊隆  你好啊  梅林[火箭]引擎太棒了
Elon, how's it going? Those Merlin engines are fantastic.
谢谢  嗯  做电动喷气机挺好
Thank you. Yeah, I've got an idea for an electric jet.
-是吗  -嗯
- You do? - Yeah.
那我们就做出来
Then we'll make it work.
-你需要按摩吗  -天呐  不要
- You want a massage? - Oh, God. No,
-我不要按摩  -我会让娜塔莉安排
- I don't want a massage. - I'll have Natalie make an appointment.
-我不要娜塔莉做什么  -你这么紧张不好
- I don't want Natalie to do... - Don't want you tense.
对了  我不是有意让你措手不及的
By the way, I didn't mean to spring this on you.
多谢考虑了
Thank you very much.
-绿色[嫉妒]不是最合适你的颜色  -拜托
- Green is not your best color. - Oh, please.
安托尼  是你吗
Anthony! Is that you?
-我在这世上最讨厌的人  -哥们
- My least favorite person on Earth. - Hey, pal.
-贾斯汀·汉默  -你好吗
- Justin Hammer. - How you doing?
你不是这里唯一开着好车的阔佬
You're not the only rich guy here with a fancy car.
你认识《名利场》杂志的克莉丝汀·艾凡哈特吧
You know Christine Everhart from Vanity Fair.
你们认识吧
You guys know each other?
-是的  -是啊
- Yes. - Yes.
-差不多吧  -认识
- Yes, roughly. - We do.
对了  大新闻  斯塔克工业的新执行总裁
BTW, big story. The new CEO of Stark Industries.
-我知道  -恭喜了
- I know. I know. - Congratulations.
如果我不能为我们的
My editor will kill me
《强势女性》特刊要到一句评论
if I don't grab a quote
我的编辑会要我命的
for our Powerful Women issue.
-可以吗  -当然
- Can I? - Sure.
她其实要为《名利场》做一篇我的专访
She's actually doing a big spread on me for Vanity Fair.
我就想顺手帮她个忙了
I thought I'd throw her a bone, you know.
-这样啊  -是吗  -是啊
- Right. - Right? - Yes.
她去年对托尼采访得很深入呢
Well, she did quite a spread on Tony last year.
她还写了报道
And she wrote a story as well.
-非常不得了  -很不错
- It was very impressive. - That was good.
-做得很好  -谢谢
- Very well done. - Thank you.
-我去洗洗  -别丢下我
- I'm gonna go wash. - Don't leave me.
-哥们  你好吗  -我挺好
- Hey, buddy. How you doing? - I'm all right.
-真帅气  -行了  这太难受了
- Looking gorgeous. - Please, this is tough.
-能问问  这是你们...  -奶酪
- Can I ask you... ls this the first time... - Fromage.
法语的奶酪
照相说奶酪[英语]相当于茄子
-说"布里干酪"  -第一次见面吗
- Say, "Brie." - that you guys have seen each other?
天呐  烦死了
God, that's so awful.
请问  这是参议院后
Listen, is it the first time
你们第一次见面吗
you've seen each other since the Senate?
自从他的合同被撤销后
Since he got his contract revoked...
-是暂缓  -就是你企图...
- Actually, it's on hold. - When you were attempting to...
我听说不是这样
That's not what I heard.
"暂缓"和"取消"之间有什么区别
What's the difference between "hold" and "canceled"?
-是啊  问得好  -说实话
- Yes, what is? - The truth?
实话是  这个先放起来吧
No. The truth is... Why don't we put that away?
实话是
The truth is,
我其实想在你的博览会上展示点东西
I'm actually hoping to present something at your Expo.
如果你发明了什么能用的东西
Well, if you invent something that works,
我肯定会给你个展位
I'll make sure I get you a slot.
-斯塔克先生  -什么事
- Mr. Stark, - Yes?
-您的拐角桌准备好了  -我今年
- your corner table is ready. - I actually
其实有展位的  是的
have a slot this year. Yes, I do.
汉默需要个展位  克莉丝汀
Hammer needs a slot, Christine.
我们开玩笑的
We kid, yeah.
我们喜欢开玩笑
We kid. We're kidders.
血毒素含量: 53%
有其他坏主意吗
Got any other bad ideas?
托尼
Tony!
托尼和我  托尼  我爱托尼·斯塔克
Listen, Tony and I... Tony... I love Tony Stark.
托尼也爱我  我们不是竞争对手
Tony loves me. We're not competitors.
他的出局为汉默工业制造了
Him being out of the picture created tremendous opportunities
大机会  是吧
for Hammer Industries, you know?
托尼和我
Everything that Tony and I
-其实是健康的  -拥有一辆
- do is a healthy... - Well, what's the use of having...
跑车的意义
and owning a race car...
-竞争关系  -不就在于驾驶它吗
- competition. - If you don't drive it?
他要去赛车吗
Is he driving?
娜塔莉  娜塔莉
Natalie. Natalie!
-是  波茨小姐  -这事你知道吗
- Yes, Miss Potts? - Did you know about this?
我也是刚知道
This is the first that I have known of it.
这绝对不行
This... This cannot happen.
当然  我明白  我要怎么帮您
Absolutely. I understand. How can I help you?
-哈皮呢  -在外面等着
- Where's Happy? - He's waiting outside.
-好  叫哈皮过来  -这就去
- Okay, get him. I need Happy. - Right away.
托尼  他
Tony's... You know, he...
我们没在竞争  知道吗
We're not competitive. You know what I mean?
嗯嗯
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You know,
-可以等我一会儿吗  -把你写的读给我听
- can you excuse me just one second? - Just read me what you wrote.
-好的  稍后  -读一下
- I will. I will, after. - Just read it back to me.
我先打个电话
But I have to make one quick phone call.
-你去哪  -这太棒了
- Where are you going? - This is great.
-我还叫了鱼子酱呢  -采访很棒
- I've got some caviar coming. - This is great stuff.
-我就回来  -看
- I'll be right back. - Look!
那是斯塔克
That's Stark.
开开
Go, go!
把住
Hang on.
-箱子给我  -给  拿着
- Give me the case. - Here. Take it.
-钥匙呢  -在我兜里
- Where's the key? - It's in my pocket.
车
Car!
天呐
Oh, my God!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
嗯
Yeah.
你是冲我还是冲他去的
Were you heading for me or him?
我是想吓唬他
I was trying to scare him.
-因为我看不出来  -你疯了吗
- 'Cause I can't tell! - Are you out of your mind?
安保需要加强
Better security.
-马上给我上车  -我被袭击了
- Get in the car right now! - I was attacked!
我们需要加强安保
We need better security.
-上车  -你是执行总裁
- Get in the car! - You're CEO.
加强安保措施
Better security measures.
天呐  太丢人了
God, it's embarrassing.
两年来第一次度假呢
First vacation in two years.
天呐
Oh, my God!
-我撞到他了  -再撞  再撞
- I got him! - Hit him again. Hit him again.
梗来自所谓"核武橄榄球"
即美国总统随身携带的核弹发射密码箱
橄榄球
Football.
-看我的  -拿着箱子  拿着
- I got him! - Take the case! Take it!
-箱子拿走  -把箱子给他
- Take the case! - Give him the case!
别撞车了
Stop banging the car!
冷静
Calm down.
天呐  天呐
God! God!
箱子给我  快点
Give me the case! Please! Come on!
你输了
You... You lose.
你输了  你输了  斯塔克
You lose. You lose, Stark.
我们查了他的指纹  毫无结果  连名字都查不到
我们去哪
这边
我们都不确定他说不说英语
他到之后一直一言不发
就五分钟
技术挺了不起  每秒循环有点低
Pretty decent tech. Cycles per second were a little low.
你本可把转速翻倍的
You could have doubled up your rotations.
你将冲击能用离子化等离子体通道击中起来
You focused the repulsor energy through ionized plasma channels.
有效但不高效
It's effective. Not very efficient.
但算是过得去的山寨
But it's a passable knock-off.
我不懂  稍加调整
I don't get it. A little fine tuning,
你本可挣大钱的
you could have made a solid paycheck.
你完全可以卖给朝鲜  中国  伊朗
You could have sold it to North Korea, China, Iran,
或者直接卖到黑市去
or gone right to the black market.
你看上去像是认识些黑道朋友
You look like you got friends in low places.
你的家族都是
You come from a family of
小偷和屠夫
thieves and butchers.
现在  就像所有有罪的人
And now, like all guilty men,
你想重写自己的历史
you try to rewrite your own history.
你忘记了
And you forget
斯塔克家族毁掉的那些生命
all the lives the Stark family has destroyed.
说到小偷  设计你是哪弄来的
Speaking of thieves, where did you get this design?
我父亲  安东·万科
My father. Anton Vanko.
我没听说过他
Well, I never heard of him.
我父亲是你还活着的原因
My father is the reason you're alive.
我还活着  是因为你有机会
The reason I'm alive is 'cause you had a shot,
你抓住了  但没打中
you took it, you missed.
是吗
Did I?
如果你可以让上帝流血
If you can make God bleed,
人们就不会再信奉他了
the people will cease to believe in him.
水里会有血  鲨鱼会围上来
And there will be blood in the water. And the sharks will come.
其实  我只需要坐在这里等着瞧
The truth, all I have to do is sit here and watch
看世界吞没你
as the world will consume you.
你要在哪里看世界吞没我
Where will you be watching the world consume me from?
对了  囚室里  我会给你寄肥皂的
That's right. A prison cell. I'll send you a bar of soap.
托尼  你走之前
Hey, Tony. Before you go,
胸膛渗入钯  痛苦的死法
palladium in the chest, painful way to die.
真是难以置信
It's just unbelievable.
斯特恩参议员  宾夕法尼亚州
斯塔克应当上交战衣
这证明灯神已被放了出来
It proves that the genie is out of the bottle
而他完全不知道自己在做什么
and this man has no idea what he's doing.
他把钢铁侠武器当做玩具
He thinks of the Iron Man weapon as a toy.
我参加的一场听证会上  斯塔克先生还坚称
I was at a hearing where Mr. Stark, in fact, was adamant
这种战衣其他地方不可能有
that these suits can't exist anywhere else,
别的地方没有  今后也不会有
don't exist anywhere else, never will exist anywhere else,
至少五到十年里都不会
at least for five to 10 years,
结果摩纳哥的事让我们意识到
and here we are in Monaco realizing,
"这种战衣已经有了"
"These suits exist now."
静音
Mute.
他其实该给我颁发勋章的
He should be giving me a medal. That's the truth.
-那是什么  -你的机上餐点
- What is that? - This is your in-flight meal.
那是你做的吗
Did you just make that?
嗯  你以为我这三小时都干吗去了
Yeah. Where do you think I've been for three hours?
托尼
Tony,
你有什么事瞒着我
what are you not telling me?
我一点也不想回家
I don't want to go home. At all.
我们取消我的生日派对
Let's cancel my birthday party and...
我们在欧洲  去威尼斯玩玩吧  斯普莱力
We're in Europe. Let's go to Venice, Cipriani.
-记得吗  -嗯
- Remember? - Oh, yes.
那里很适合
It's a great place to
-健健康康的  -我觉得现在时机不合适
- be healthy. - I don't think this is the right time.
我们处于麻烦中呢
We're in kind of a mess.
是啊  或许正因如此才最合适
Yeah, but maybe that's why it's the best time.
-因为我们  -我觉得作为执行总裁
- 'Cause then we... - Well, I think as the CEO,
我必须露面
I need to show up.
作为执行总裁  你可以休假的
As CEO, you are entitled to a leave.
-休假  -公司度假村
- A leave? - A company retreat.
-度假  在这样的时候  -就去玩玩
- A retreat? During a time like this? - Just a ride.
我就是提议给自己充充电
Well, I'm just saying, to recharge our batteries
把事情都考虑清楚
and figure it all out.
不是每个人都是用电的  托尼
Not everybody runs on batteries, Tony.
土豆慢用
他来了
There he is.
真是太荣幸了  欢迎
What an absolute pleasure. Welcome.
老天爷啊
Oh, goodness gracious.
能不能给我的朋友解开手铐
Can we get the handcuffs off my friend here?
请原谅  抱歉  我是你的大粉丝啊
Forgive me, I'm sorry. I'm such a huge fan of yours.
我没想留下这样的第一印象的
I didn't want to make a first impression like this.
他又不是动物  拜托
He's not an animal. Come on.
他可是个人  谢谢
He's a human being. Thank you.
没事了
We're fine.
我叫贾斯汀·汉默
My name is Justin Hammer.
我想跟你做生意  请坐
I'd like to do some business with you. Please sit.
开动吧  今天吃什么  杰克
Dig in. What do we have today, Jack?
-意式生鲜鲑鱼片  -意式生鲜鲑鱼片
- We have some salmon carpaccio. - Salmon carpaccio.
你想要什么  我们都有
Anything you want here, we got it.
我喜欢先吃甜点  叫人从旧金山送来的
I like my dessert first. I had this flown in from San Francisco.
但是意大利式的
It's Italian, though.
有机冰淇淋
Organic ice cream.
我喜欢吃甜的
I got a sweet tooth.
看来你是跟托尼·斯塔克有仇啊
Apparently you do, too, for Tony Stark.
我看到你在赛道上对托尼·斯塔克做的事
What I saw you do to Tony Stark on that track,
你当着上帝和每个人的面去挑战他
how you stepped up to him in front of God and everybody,
那简直...
that was...
你的作为触动了我
You spoke to me with what you did.
我知道你知道  我会愿意倾听
And I know that you knew that I'd be listening.
所以我无法忍受你被转移去
This is why I couldn't bear to have you shipped off
天晓得哪里  那多么浪费才能
to God knows where. It would have been such a waste of talent.
但容我提议
But if I might make a suggestion,
你不能就那么冲上去企图杀了他
you know, you don't just go and try and kill the guy.
容我说  你要打击他的遗产
I think, if I may, you go after his legacy.
那才是你该扼杀的
That's what you kill.
你和我  我们在很多方面很像
You and me, we are a lot alike in a lot of ways.
你和我唯一的区别是  我有很多资源
The only difference between you and I is that I have resources.
我觉得  容我说
I think, if I may,
你需要我的资源
you need my resources.
一个背后支持你的资助人
Someone behind you, a benefactor.
我想来资助你
I'd like to be that guy.
好吧
Okay.
你说英语吗  我可以去找个翻译
Do you speak English? Because I can get a translator.
我不知道  我刚刚说的你都听懂了吗
I don't know. Have you been understanding everything I'm saying?
很好  哥们
Very good, man.
-很好  哥们  -很好  哥们
- Very good, man. - Very good, man.
怎么
Yes?
我要我的鸟
I want my bird.
-鸟  你要只鸟  -我要我的鸟
- A bird? You want a bird? - I want my bird.
我可以给你鸟  十只都没问题
I can get you a bird. I can get you 10 birds.
我要我的鸟
I want my bird.
好吧  没什么是不可能的  我可以
Well, okay. Nothing's impossible. I could...
这是...一只俄罗斯的鸟吗
Are we talking about... ls this a bird back in Russia?
是的  但是公司的
Yes, but the fundamentals
根基仍然非常坚实
of the company are still very, very strong
-不管在摩纳哥发生了什么  -当然
- despite the events in Monaco. - Yes, of course.
-美联社要评论  -别说  发传真
- The AP wants a quote. - Don't tell him. Fax them...
他在哪
Where is he?
-他不想被打扰  -他在楼下
- He doesn't want to be disturbed. - He's downstairs.
-发生在摩纳哥的事  -是啊
- what happened in Monaco? - Yes, well...
托尼·斯塔克发表声明
但他持续不断的古怪行为
But his continuing erratic behavior
或许会让很多人自问
may lead many people to ask themselves,
"这人还能保护我们吗"
"Can this man still protect us?"
钢铁侠从未停止保护我们
Iron Man never stopped protecting us.
摩纳哥的事件证明了这点
The events in Monaco proved that.
搜索完成了  先生
Query complete, sir.
安东·万科是一位苏联物理学家
Anton Vanko was a Soviet physicist
苏联科学家万科叛逃
物理学家在美国寻求庇护
他于1963年叛逃至美国
who defected to the United States in 1963.
但是  他被控间谍罪
However, he was accused of espionage
并于1967年被驱逐出境
and was deported in 1967.
苏联科学家被控间谍罪
万科被判犯下间谍罪
他的儿子  伊凡  也是个物理学家
His son, Ivan, who is also a physicist,
俄罗斯物理学家被定罪
他因将苏联时期的
was convicted of selling
武器级钯卖给巴基斯坦而被定罪
Soviet-era weapons-grade plutonium to Pakistan,
科学家因贩卖钯而被捕
在克匹亚斯监狱服刑了15年
and served 15 years in Kopeisk prison.
伊凡·万科被判刑15年
之后便再无记录
No further records exist.
托尼  你得马上
Tony, you gotta get upstairs
上楼去  控制局面
and get on top of this situation right now.
听着  我跟国民警卫队通话一整天了
Listen. I've been on the phone with the National Guard all day,
努力说服他们不要把坦克开上太平洋海岸高速
trying to talk them out of rolling tanks up the PCH,
撞倒你的前门  夺走这些战衣
knocking down your front door and taking these.
他们要拿走你的战衣  托尼  好吗
They're gonna take your suits, Tony, okay?
他们不想再跟你玩游戏了
They're sick of the games.
你曾说20年内不会有其他人拥有这项技术
You said nobody else would possess this technology for 20 years.
你猜怎么  有人昨天就拥有了
Well, guess what? Somebody else had it yesterday.
已经不是理论了
It's not theoretical anymore.
你在听吗
Are you listening to me?
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我们走
Let's go.
哥们
Hey, man.
-你没事吧  -嗯  我得到桌子前
- You all right? - Yeah, I should get to my desk.
-看到那个雪茄盒了吗  -嗯
- See that cigar box? - Yeah.
里面是钯
It's palladium.
那玩意该冒烟的吗
Is that supposed to be smoking?
如果你非要问  那是中子损伤
If you must know, it's neutron damage.
是反应堆壁冒的烟
It's from the reactor wall.
你把这个插进身体里
You had this in your body?
那你脖子上的高科技填字游戏又是怎么回事
And how about the high-tech crossword puzzle on your neck?
擦伤
Road rash.
谢谢
Thank you.
-你在看什么  -我在看你
- What are you looking at? - I'm looking at you.
你非要装出一套孤独枪手的样子
You wanna do this whole lone gunslinger act
根本没必要  你不用一个人扛的
and it's unnecessary. You don't have to do this alone.
我真希望我能相信这话  真的
You know, I wish I could believe that. I really do.
但你得相信我
But you've gotta trust me.
不管别人怎么说  我其实清楚自己在做什么
Contrary to popular belief, I know exactly what I'm doing.
纽约市  皇后区
汉默
我们就在这里工作  这里是我的寒舍
This is where we do it. This is my humble abode.
你可以安心工作了  作为死人肯定很好玩吧
You can work in absolute peace. Must be fun to be dead, right?
没有压力
No pressure.
在这里呢  很令人激动  可以作战的
Here they are. I'm very excited. They're combat-ready.
我可能错算了一些地方
I may have done a few miscalculations
太急着生产原型机了
and rushed the prototype into production.
没办法  我太热忱了嘛
Sue me, I'm enthusiastic.
去看看吧
Go ahead, take a look around.
你最好别那么做
You don't wanna do that.
等我们生成了
You'll be able to access that
加密密码  你就可以访问了
as soon as we generate some encrypted pass codes.
可以生成一些加密密码吗
Can we generate some encrypted pass codes?
去拿点加密密码来  杰克
Get some of those encrypted pass codes, Jack.
准许访问
不用了
Never mind, I...
好啊  厉害
Okay. Good stuff.
-什么  -软件太烂
- Sorry? - Software shit.
好吧
Well...
你很厉害
You're good.
你直接冲破了防火墙
You really blasted in past the firewall there.
我带你去看你主要的工作场所吧
Let me show you where you're gonna be working primarily.
去看看吧
Go ahead, take a look.
好好看看吧  挺不错的  是吧
Get a good look at that. That's something, isn't it?
那其实只是用来做展示的
You know, those are really just for show and tell.
每个价值1.257亿  所以  等等
They're $125.7 million a pop, so... Wait!
老天爷啊
Oh, gosh.
老天啊  叫个人过来
Jesus Christ. Get somebody up here.
那是驾驶员待的地方
That's where the pilot goes.
我不太能找到志愿者
I'm having a tough time finding volunteers.
交给我处理吧  别管了
I'll take care of that, just leave it.
你想要它们做什么
What you want them do?
长期来讲  我希望它们
Well, long term, I want them
能让我成为五角大楼接下来25年的合作者
to put me in the Pentagon for the next 25 years.
我想把钢铁侠比得像古董
I want to make Iron Man look like an antique.
我想去斯塔克博览会
I wanna go to that Stark Expo,
然后在托尼前院里拉泡屎
I wanna take a dump in Tony's front yard.
你明白我的意思吗
You know what I'm talking about?
-我做得到  没问题  -是吗
- I can do that. No problem. - Yeah?
太棒了  我喜欢
Hey, fabulous! I love it.
这就是我们的贵人  我早说的吧
Hey, this is our guy. Didn't I tell you?
我早料到了
I had a feeling.
钯浓度89%
您今晚要戴哪块表  斯塔克先生
Do you know which watch you'd like to wear tonight, Mr. Stark?
我看看
I'll give them a look.
我该取消派对
I should cancel the party.
-或许吧  -是啊
- Probably. - Yeah.
-因为  -时机不合适
- 'Cause it's... - Ill-timed.
是啊  发出错误的讯息
Right, sends the wrong message.
不得体
Inappropriate.
橄榄汁加得够吗[够淫荡吗]
Is that dirty enough for you?
金表面  棕色表带  积家  拿来我看看
Gold face, brown band. The Jaeger. I'll give that a look.
拿过来
Bring them over here.
给我吧  你去
I'll take that. Why don't you...
我得说  你让人捉摸不透
I gotta say it. It's hard to get a read on you.
-你是哪里来的  -法律部
- Where are you from? - Legal.
能问你个假设问题吗
Can I ask you a question, hypothetically?
有点怪
Bit Odd.
如果这是你最后一个生日派对了
If this was your last birthday party you were ever gonna have,
你会怎么庆祝
how would you celebrate it?
我会做我想做的事
I'd do whatever I wanted to do
跟我想要的人一起做
with whoever I wanted to do it with.
-晚上好  -晚上好
- Good evening. - Good evening.
是  长官  我懂
Yes, sir, I understand.
不  长官  没那个必要  我会处理的
No. No, sir, that will not be necessary. I'll handle it.
长官  我亲自担保  24小时内
Sir, I personally guarantee that within 24 hours,
钢铁侠就会继续守卫
Iron Man will be back on watch.
派珀
Hey, Pepper.
我要去喘口气
I'm going to go get some air.
怎么了
What's wrong?
-我不知道该怎么办  -开什么玩笑
- I don't know what to do. - You gotta be kidding me.
行了  我要
That's it. I'm making...
-不不不  别叫人来  -派珀
- No, no, no. Don't call anyone. - Pepper.
这太荒谬了  我才刚替他做了担保
This is ridiculous. I just stuck my neck out for this guy.
我知道  我懂
I know. I know. I get it.
我会处理的  好吗  让我来处理
I'm gonna handle it, okay? Just let me handle it.
处理吧  否则我就要出手了
Handle it. Or I'm gonna have to.
别人最经常问我的问题是
You know, the question I get asked most often is,
"托尼  你穿着这战衣怎么如厕"
"Tony, how do you go to the bathroom in the suit?"
就这样
Just like that.
这家伙是不是最会开派对了
Does this guy know how to throw a party or what?
我爱你
I love you.
难以置信  非常感谢
Unbelievable! Thank you so much.
托尼  我们都感谢你带来了这么美好的一晚
Tony, we all thank you so much for such a wonderful night.
我们要道晚安了  感谢大家到来
And we're gonna say good night now, and thank you all for coming.
不不  不可以  等等
No, no, no, we can't... Wait, wait, wait.
我们还没吃蛋糕  还没吹蜡烛呢
We didn't have the cake. We didn't blow out the candles.
你太失控了  这你得相信我
You're out of control, okay? Trust me on this one, okay?
-你才失控呢  美女  -该去睡了
- You're out of control, gorgeous. - It's time to go to bed.
到时间了
It's time.
-再来吻一个  -你不会如愿的
- Give me another smooch. - You're not going to be happy about this.
得了  你也想的
Come on, you know you want to.
你刚在战衣里撒了尿
You just peed the suit.
-我知道  它有过滤系统  -这不性感
- I know. It has a filtration system. - It's not sexy.
这水都能喝的
You could drink that water.
叫大家都回家去  你该...
Just send everybody home, okay? It's time to...
-听你的  -好
- If you say so. - Okay.
这个给我  这个给你
I'll take this, you take that.
派珀·波茨
Pepper Potts.
她说得对  派对结束了
She's right. The party's over.
不过  对于我
Then again, the party was over
派对在一个半小时前就结束了
for me, like, an hour and a half ago.
余兴派对15分钟后开始
The after-party starts in 15 minutes.
如果有人  派珀  不喜欢  门在那里
And if anybody, Pepper, doesn't like it, there's the door.
好啊
Yeah!
丢
Hit!
放
Pull!
她是想要我用大炮
I think she wants the Gallagher!
我就说这一次
I'm only gonna say this once.
出去
Get out.
你不配穿这战衣  关闭它
You don't deserve to wear one of these. Shut it down!
戈德斯登
Goldstein.
什么事  斯塔克先生
Yes, Mr. Stark?
我要扁我哥们  给我们奏乐
Give me a phat beat to beat my buddy's ass to.
我叫你关掉它了
I told you to shut it down.
把那玩意哪拿的放回哪去
Now, put that thing back where you found it
别害谁受伤了
before someone gets hurt.
不是吧
Really?
抱歉  哥们  但钢铁侠不要跟班
Sorry, pal, but Iron Man doesn't have a sidekick.
跟你妹
Sidekick this!
够了没有
Had enough?
-娜塔莉  -波茨小姐
- Natalie! - Miss Potts.
少来什么"波茨小姐"  我识破你了
Don't you "Miss Potts" me! I'm on to you.
知道吗  自从你来了之后...
You know what? Ever since you came here...
派珀
Pepper!
快出去  快走
Get out of here. Get out of here.
你要吗  接招吧
You want it? Take it!
把手放下
Put your hand down.
你觉得你有能力穿这件战衣吗
You think you got what it takes to wear that suit?
我们不用这样的  托尼
We don't have to do this, Tony.
你想做战争机器  动手吧
You wanna be the War Machine, take your shot.
-放下  -你要开火吗
- Put it down! - You gonna take a shot?
-放下  -不
- Put it down! - No!
-放下  托尼  -接招
- Drop it, Tony! - Take it.
爱德华兹空军基地
加州  莫哈韦沙漠
爱德华兹塔楼  我是詹姆斯·罗德中校
Edwards Tower, this is Lieutenant Colonel James Rhodes,
正在从东三英里处飞入  高度五千英尺
inbound from three miles east at 5,000 feet...
中校
Colonel.
少校
Major.
是啊
Yeah.
我们进去吧
Let's take it inside.
让让地方
Clear the area.
兰迪甜甜圈
先生
Sir!
我要请你从甜甜圈上下来
I'm gonna have to ask you to exit the donut.
我告诉你我不想加入你的绝密男子组合了
I told you I don't wanna join your super-secret boy band.
不不
No, no, no.
瞧  我记得  你什么事都自己干
See, I remember, you do everything yourself.
-结果怎么样呢  -挺...
- How's that working out for you? - It's... It's... It's...
抱歉  我不想惹到你
I'm sorry. I don't wanna get off on the wrong foot.
我是该看眼罩还是眼睛
Do I look at the patch or the eye?
老实说  我有点宿醉
Honestly, I'm a bit hung over.
我都不确定你是真的  还是我...
I'm not sure if you're real or if I'm having...
我非常真实
I am very real.
我是你会认识的最真实的人
I'm the realest person you're ever gonna meet.
真走运  这里的员工呢
Just my luck. Where's the staff here?
那看上去不妙啊
That's not looking so good.
我经历过更糟的
I've been worse.
我们已封锁周边了
We've secured the perimeter,
但恐怕维持不了很久
but I don't think we should hold it for too much longer.
你被解雇了
You're fired.
那不由你决定
That's not up to you.
托尼  这位是罗曼诺夫特工
Tony, I want you to meet Agent Romanoff.
我是个神盾局影子特工
I'm a S.H.L.E.L.D. shadow.
我们发现你生病后
Once we knew you were ill,
弗瑞局长就派我潜到你身边
I was tasked to you by Director Fury.
我建议你道歉
I suggest you apologize.
你最近很忙啊
You've been very busy.
让你女朋友当上执行总裁
You made your girl your CEO,
把东西都捐了出去
you're giving away all your stuff.
让你的朋友穿着你的战衣飞走了
You let your friend fly away with your suit.
如果我不了解...
Now, if I didn't know better...
你的确不了解  我没给他  是他自己夺的
You don't know better. I didn't give it to him. He took it.
他夺的
What? He took it?
你是钢铁侠  他想夺就夺了
You're Iron Man and he just took it'?
那位黑人兄弟走进去
The little brother walked in there,
扁了你一顿  然后夺了一件你的战衣
kicked your ass and took your suit?
这可能吗
Is that possible?
根据斯塔克先生的数据库安保指导
Well, according to Mr. Stark's database security guidelines,
有冗余规程防止未授权使用的
there are redundancies to prevent unauthorized usage.
-你们想要什么  -我们想要什么
- What do you want from me? - What do we want from you?
你想要什么
What do you want from me?
你已经成了个问题  而我得解决你这个问题
You have become a problem, a problem I have to deal with.
不管你怎么想  你不是我宇宙的中心
Contrary to your belief, you are not the center of my universe.
我在西南部
I have bigger problems
还有比你更大的问题要处理
than you in the southwest region to deal with.
给他
Hit him.
天呐  你们要挖了我的肾去卖吗
Oh, God, are you gonna steal my kidney and sell it?
你能不能坚持五秒别干什么坏事
Could you please not do anything awful for five seconds?
-她刚对我做了什么  -我们刚为你做了什么
- What did she just do to me? - What did we just do for you?
那是二氧化锂  能缓解你的病症
That's lithium dioxide. It's gonna take the edge off.
我们是想让你回去工作
We're trying to get you back to work.
给我几盒那玩意  我就没问题了
Give me a couple of boxes of that. I'll be right as rain.
不能治愈  只能缓解症状
It's not a cure, it just abates the symptoms.
看上去解决办法不会很简单的
Doesn't look like it's gonna be an easy fix.
相信我  我知道  我擅长这玩意的
Trust me, I know. I'm good at this stuff.
我一直在寻找合适的钯替代物
I've been looking for a suitable replacement for palladium.
我试过了每一种组合
I've tried every combination,
每一种已知元素的排列方式
every permutation of every known element.
我要告诉你  你还没试全
Well, I'm here to tell you, you haven't tried them all.
特别快递
Special delivery.
糖果电报
Candygram.
我拿了东西给你
I brought you something.
好啊
Oh, yeah.
我们把你的鸟拿来了  哥们
We got you the bird, pal.
这不是我的鸟
This is not my bird.
什么  就是它啊  就是这个
What do you mean? That's the bird. This is the bird.
是啊  为此动用了不少关系呢
Yeah. Pulled a lot of strings to get this bird.
这只鸟很棒
This is a great bird.
-很美  -从俄罗斯远道而来的
- It's a beautiful bird. - We got this all the way from Russia.
我说这不是我的鸟
Hey, man, this not my bird.
听着  就算不是
Well, listen, even if it's not the bird,
这也是只很美的鸟
I mean, this is a gorgeous bird.
别对身外物那么执迷嘛
I mean, you know, look, don't get so attached to things.
学会放手
Learn to let go.
等等  杰克  那是什么
Wait a minute. Jack, what is that?
那...那不是头盔  那是什么
Is that... That's not a helmet. What is that?
伊凡  这是什么
Ivan... What's this?
杰克
Jack.
那是头盔吗  我看不像
Is that a helmet? It doesn't look like a helmet to me.
这玩意要怎么戴在脑袋上
How... How are you supposed to get a head in there?
-杰克  你的脑袋能放进去吗  -不能
- Jack, could you put your head in there? - No.
试试把脑袋放进去
Try to put your head in there.
试试吧  看能不能把脑袋放进去
Go ahead. Try to put your head in there.
看  伊凡  他不能把脑袋放进去
See, Ivan? He can't put his head in there.
这不是头盔
That's... That's not a helmet.
而是脑袋  我得让人进去
It's a head. I need to put a guy in there.
我得让战衣里能进个人  明白吗
I need to fit a person in that suit. You understand?
-无人机更好  -什么  无人机更好
- Drone better. - What? Drone better?
为什么  为什么无人机更好
Why is drone better? Why is drone better?
人会制造问题
People make problem.
相信我  无人机更好
Trust me. Drone better.
伊凡  我喜欢你  我给你把鸟拿来了
Ivan, you know, I like you. I got you the bird.
你说"没问题"的
You said, "No problem."
你是跟我这么说的  你说"没问题"
That's what you said to me. You said, "No problem."
我需要战衣  政府要战衣
Now I need suits. The government wants suits.
就像钢铁侠  懂吗
Like Iron Man. You understand?
那才是人们要的  那会让他们开心
That's what the people want. That's what's gonna make them happy.
哥们
Hey, man.
别太执迷于身外物
Don't get too attached to things.
学会放手
Learn to let go.
这些无人机最好能抢风头  伊凡
These drones better steal the show, Ivan.
明白吗  最好让我震撼  伊凡
You understand? Better rock my world, Ivan.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
这应该足以让参议院放过我了
This ought to get the Senate off my ass.
-可以用吗  -完全能执行任务
- It's functional? - Fully mission-capable.
很好  让汉默过来把它武器化
Good. Get Hammer down here to weaponize it.
长官
Sir?
贾斯汀·汉默要在博览会上进行武器展示
Justin Hammer's making a weapons presentation at the Expo.
我们要用它进行介绍
We'd like this to introduce it.
长官  我不觉得博览会
Sir, I don't believe that the Expo...
中校  得尽快让世界看到它
Colonel, the world needs to see this fast.
-我们必须做到  -是  将军  但是
- We've got to make this happen. - Yes, General, but...
这还是命令
It's also an order.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
好样的  中校  国家以你为傲
Good work, Colonel. You've made your country proud.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
你胸口的那玩意是基于未完成的科技
That thing in your chest is based on unfinished technology.
不  是完成的
No, it was finished.
但此前并不是很高效
It has never been particularly effective
直到我把它缩小  放进了我的...
until I miniaturized it and put it in my...
不  霍华德说方舟反应堆
No. Howard said the arc reactor
是通向更伟大发明的垫脚石
was the stepping stone to something greater.
他本来要开展能源竞赛
He was about to kick off an energy race
把军备竞赛远远地比下去
that was gonna dwarf the arms race.
他在研究什么大项目
He was on to something big,
大到能把核反应堆比得像
something so big that it was gonna make the nuclear reactor
3A电池的东西
look like a triple-A battery.
就他一人吗  还是安东·万科也参加了
Just him, or was Anton Vanko in on this, too?
安东·万科是硬币的另一面
Anton Vanko is the other side of that coin.
安东把这视为生财之道
Anton saw it as a way to get rich.
你父亲发现后  将他驱逐出境了
When your father found out, he had him deported.
而当苏联发现他光说不能做时
When the Russians found out he couldn't deliver,
就把他送去了西伯利亚
they shipped his ass off to Siberia
接下来20年里  伏特加让他越来越愤怒
and he spent the next 20 years in a vodka-fuelled rage.
那并不是养孩子的好环境
Not quite the environment you want to raise a kid in,
你不幸在摩纳哥遭遇了他的儿子
the son you had the misfortune of crossing paths with in Monaco.
你跟我说  我还没试全
You told me I hadn't tried everything.
什么意思  我没试全
What do you mean I haven't tried everything?
我还有什么没试的
What haven't I tried?
他说
He said that
你是唯一有办法有知识
you were the only person with the means and knowledge
完成他未竟事业的人
to finish what he started.
这是他说的
He said that?
你是那样的人吗  是吗
Are you that guy? Are you?
因为如果你是
'Cause if you are,
那你就能解决你心脏的谜题
then you can solve the riddle of your heart.
我不知道你的情报哪来的
I don't know where you get your information,
但他并没那么喜欢我
but he wasn't my biggest fan.
你对你爸爸都记得什么
What do you remember about your dad?
他很冷漠  算计
He was cold, he was calculating.
他从不对我说他爱我  甚至不说他喜欢我
He never told me he loved me. He never even told me he liked me,
所以我有点难以相信
so it's a little tough for me to digest
你说他曾说未来全靠我了
when you're telling me he said the whole future was riding on me
还说他传承给我了  我不理解
and he's passing it down. I don't get that.
这家伙最开心的一天
You're talking about a guy whose happiest day
就是把我送去寄宿学校的那天
was when he shipped me off to boarding school.
才不是这样
That's not true.
那你显然比我更了解我爸
Well, then, clearly you knew my dad better than I did.
其实  还真是这样
As a matter of fact, I did.
他是神盾局的创建者之一
He was one of the founding members of S.H.I.E.L.D.
什么
What?
-我2点还有安排  -等等
- I got a 2:00. - Wait, wait, wait, wait.
-这是什么  -你没事了吧
- What's this? - Okay, you're good, right?
-不  我有事  -你可以了吧  是吧
- No, I'm not good. - You got this? Right? Right?
可以什么  我根本没听明白
Got what? I don't even know what I'm supposed to get.
娜塔莎会继续以伪装身份待在斯塔克工业
Natasha will remain a floater at Stark with her cover intact.
-你记得科尔森特工吧  -嗯
- You remember Agent Coulson, right? - Yeah.
托尼
And Tony,
记住  我看着你呢
remember, I got my eye on you.
我们切断了所有通讯
We've disabled all communications.
不能与外界接触
No contact with the outside world.
祝你好运
Good luck.
拜托
Please.
首先  我需要身行头
First thing, I need a little bodywork.
我会去实验室忙活一会儿
I'll put in a little time at the lab.
如果能麻烦你的哪个手下去趟
If we could send one of your goon squad down to The Coffee Bean,
连锁咖啡店买点咖啡回来
Cross Creek, for a Starbucks run, or something like that,
就太棒了
that'd be nice.
我不是来做那个的
I'm not here for that.
弗瑞局长授权我
I've been authorized by Director Fury
使用一切手段阻止你离开这里
to use any means necessary to keep you on premises.
-如果你企图离开  -好吧
- If you attempt to leave - Right.
或是耍花招
or play any games,
我就电击你  然后去看《超级保姆》
I will tase you and watch Supernanny
任你往地毯上流口水
while you drool into the carpet.
-好吗  -我懂了
- Okay? - I think I got it, yeah.
祝你晚上愉快
Enjoy your evening's entertainment.
H·斯塔克私产
你觉得这是能源吗
Think this is the power source?
少校  这不是科学练习
Major, this is not a scientific exercise.
我们赶紧给它装配武器吧
Let's just focus on arming it, all right?
是  长官
Yes, sir.
太好了
Oh, yes!
Oh, yes, yes, yes.
今天是我生日吗
ls it my birthday?
你拿到了  你做了什么
You got it. What did you do?
你做了什么
What did you do?
-这是我想的那个东西吗  -是的
- Is this what I think it is? - Yes, it is.
汉默  我想知道你要为我们做什么
Hammer, I want to know what you're gonna do for us.
我要为你们做什么
What am I going to do for you?
首先我要为你们做的
Well, the first thing I'm gonna do for you
是升级你们的软件
is I'm gonna upgrade your software.
然后  我想...
And then, second, I think I should...
我不是问那个  汉默
That's not what I'm talking about. Hammer.
我是问火力
I'm talking about firepower.
那你找对人了
Well, you're talking to the right guy.
克拉里奇高科技  半自动  9毫米手枪
Claridge Hi-Tec, semi-automatic, 9mm pistol.
太小了吗  我同意
Too downtown? I agree.
M24霰弹猎枪  压动式枪机
M24 shotgun, pump action.
五弹弹匣
Five-round magazine.
算了  你又不是猎人
You know what? You're not a hunter.
我说什么呢  这个不要了
What am I talking about? I'm getting rid of it.
这是比利时的FN2000
This is the FN-2000 from Belgium.
他们真有比华夫饼做得好的东西
They do make something better than waffles.
很漂亮  但我看得出你们还嫌不够劲儿
It's beautiful, but I can tell this isn't disco enough for you,
所以我还是把它放这里了
so I'm gonna put it right here.
这是米尔科尔40毫米榴弹发射器
You're looking at a Milkor 40mm grenade launcher.
催泪瓦斯  烟雾  操控简单
Tear gas, smoke. Hippie control.
你们真不好取悦
You're tough.
告诉你们  大小是很重要的
Let me tell you something. Size does matter.
别听人说不重要
Don't let anyone tell you different.
这是米尼岗M134式7.62毫米机枪
This is an M134 7.62 Minigun.
六个独立枪管  粉骨碎身  灰飞烟灭
Six individual barrels. The torso taker, powder maker.
军队的小伙子们称之为凉菜汤大叔
Our boys in uniform call it Uncle Gazpacho,
或魔龙之息
or Puff the Magic Dragon.
好吧
Okay.
这可是好货
These are the Cubans, baby.
就像古巴的名牌雪茄
This is the Cohibas, the Montecristos.
这是动能杀伤响尾蛇导弹载体
This is a kinetic-kill, side-winder vehicle
还有二级的环三亚甲基三硝胺黑索今爆炸
with a secondary cyclotrimethylenetrinitramine RDX burst.
能炸开
It's capable of busting
你刚刚炸开的地堡下的地堡
the bunker under the bunker you just busted.
如果它再智能点  都能写书了
If it were any smarter, it would write a book.
这本书能把《尤利西斯》
A book that would make Ulysses
比得像是用蜡笔写的
look like it was written in crayon.
它还能给你念出来
It would read it to you.
这是我的埃菲尔铁塔
This is my Eiffel Tower.
是我的拉赫玛尼诺夫第三协奏曲  我的杰作
This is my Rachmaninoff's Third. My Pieté.
非常典雅  美得难以置信
It's completely elegant. It's bafflingly beautiful.
而且能将任何
It's capable of reducing
建筑物内的人口减少至零
the population of any standing structure to zero.
我称它为"前妻"
I call it the Ex-Wife.
这是我最棒的了
That's the best I got.
我们还做不做了  给点反应嘛
Are we gonna do this? Give me something here.
你就像斯芬克斯  让我猜不透
You're like a sphinx. I can't read you.
我要了
I think I'll take it.
哪一个
Which one?
全要
All of it.
方舟反应堆  安东·万科  霍华德·斯塔克
苏联科学家万科叛逃
物理学家在美国寻求庇护
博览会介绍
科技可以实现一切
Everything is achievable through technology.
更好的生活  强健的体魄
Better living, robust health,
以及人类史上第一次
and for the first time in human history,
世界和平的可能性
the possibility of world peace.
我是霍华德·斯塔克
I'm Howard Stark,
你在未来
and everything you'll need
需要的一切  这里都有
for the future can be found right here.
未来之城  明日之城  还是...
City of the Future? City of Tomorrow? City of...
我是霍华德·斯塔克
I'm Howard Stark,
你在未来需要的一切  这里都有
and everything you'll need in the future can be found right here.
所以  代表斯塔克工业全体
So, from all of us at Stark Industries,
我要亲自...
I would like to personally...
托尼  你在那里干什么呢  那是什么
Tony, what are you doing back there? What is that?
放回去  哪里拿的放回去
Put that back. Put it back where you got it from.
你妈妈呢  玛丽亚
Where's your mother? Maria?
快点  快走
Go on. Go, go, go, go.
好了  我们...
All right, I think we got...
我再走一遍
I'll... l'll... l'll come in and...
你在等我吗
Are you waiting on me?
所以  代表斯塔克工业全体
So, from all of us at Stark Industries,
我要亲自向你介绍
I'd like to personally show you
我的屁股
my ass.
我想...不行
I'd like to... I can't... This is...
真是的  拍好了吧
I can't... We have this, don't we?
真是荒唐
This is a ridiculous way...
科技
Everything
可以
is achievable
实现一切
through technology.
托尼
Tony?
你还太小  现在不会理解
You're too young to understand this right now,
所以我还是录下来给你看吧
so I thought I would put it on film for you.
我建这个是为了你
I built this for you.
总有一天  你会明白这远不仅仅
And someday you'll realize that it represents a whole lot more
只是人们的发明  这是我一生的心血
than just people's inventions. It represents my life's work.
这是通往未来的钥匙
This is the key to the future.
我受我现在时代的科技所限制
I'm limited by the technology of my time,
但有一天你能解开它
but one day you'll figure this out.
到时候
And when you do,
你将能改变世界
you will change the world.
我这辈子  自始至终
What is and always will be
最伟大的创造
my greatest creation
就是你
is you.
-六美元  -我没拿现金
- $6. Six. - I don't have any dough.
-给  -不  先生  这太多了
- Here. - No, sir, that's too much.
没事的  拿着吧
No, it's fine. Take that.
-没事的  -不  先生
- It's fine. - No, sefior.
拿着吧  我不喜欢被人递东西
Take it. Take it. I don't like people handing me things.
放在那里就好  很好
If you just drop that there, that'd be great.
-你是钢铁侠吗  -有时候吧
- Are you Iron Man? - Sometimes.
我们相信你
We believe in you.
那是对商业资产的违法扣押
It was an illegal seizure of trademark property.
-波茨小姐  -放松
- Miss Potts? - Relax.
-斯塔克先生  -来了
- Mr. Stark... - Is here.
-他不肯  -是啊  没事的
- He refuses... - I don't. It's fine.
-马上就完  -听着  我们的立场是
- I'll just be a second. - Listen, it's our position
斯塔克工业拥有且仍然拥有
that Stark has and continues to maintain
马克2号平台的所有权
proprietary ownership of the Mark II platform.
斯塔克先生宣布他就是钢铁侠时
When Mr. Stark announced he was indeed Iron Man,
他向美国做出了一个承诺
he was making a promise to America.
托尼·斯塔克完了
不  战衣是我们的
No, the suit belongs to us.
我们相信他会守护我们
We trusted that he would look out for us.
-是啊  但你不...  -他显然没有
- Yeah, but you're not... - He obviously did not.
伯特
Burt...
-现在我们得知他的秘书  -是的
- And now we learn that his secretary... - Yes, it does.
名叫维吉尼亚·"派珀"·波茨的女人
a woman named Virginia "Pepper" Potts,
被任命为斯塔克工业的执行总裁
has been appointed as CEO of Stark Industries.
她有什么资质
What are her qualifications?
-不  -波茨小姐完全没有
- No. - Ms. Potts is doing nothing
控制住这场糟糕的...
to manage this terrible...
-静音  -不
- Mute. - No...
伯特  伯特  听我说
Burt... Burt... Burt, listen to me.
别告诉我我们有全国最好的专利律师
Don't tell me that we have the best patent lawyers in the country
还不许我提出诉讼
and then not let me pursue this.
我会把这些东西搬走的
I'll get this stuff out of here.
那就叫总统签个命令啊
Well, then, tell the President to sign an order.
我们到博览会上谈
We'll talk about it at the Expo.
汉默明晚要做什么展示
Hammer's giving some presentation tomorrow evening.
-托尼·斯塔克会去吗  -我会吗
- Will Tony Stark be there? - Will I?
-不  他不会  -我想去的
- No, he will not.  - I would like to be.
再见
Bye.
-有空吗  -没有
- Got a minute? - No.
拜托  你刚挂了电话
Come on, you just got off the phone.
又没什么事  就30秒
You're fine, 30 seconds.
-29  28  -好吧  我...
- Twenty-nine. Twenty-eight. - Okay, I...
我刚开车过来的
I was just driving over here,
我本以为我是要来道歉的  但不是的
and I thought I was coming to basically apologize, but I'm not.
-你不是来道歉的  -听着
- You didn't come here to apologize? - Look,
这是不用说的
that goes without saying,
我在努力了
and I'm working on that.
但我没有完全对你说实话
But I haven't been entirely upfront with you,
我想做正确的事
and I just want to try to make good.
我能把这个挪开吗  简直疯了
Can I move this? This is crazy.
简直像个摩天轮
It's like a Ferris wheel going.
-我还想...  -不行
- I'm trying to get some... - No.
你知道人生多短吗
Do you know how short life is?
如果我从没表达...
And if I never got to express...
对了  这对我来说也挺有启示性
And by the way, this is somewhat revelatory to me.
我不在乎...我在乎的  那样就好了
And I don't care... I mean, I care. It would be nice.
我不指望你...
I'm not expecting you to...
我想说的是
Look, here's what I'm trying to say.
-我直说了吧  -你打住吧
- I'm just gonna say it. - Let me stop you right here, okay?
因为如果你再说一个"我"
Because if you say "I" one more time,
我真的要拿什么东西砸你的脑袋了
I'm gonna actually hurl something at your head, I think.
我在努力管理一家公司
I am trying to run a company.
-你知道那都包括做什么吗  -知道
- Do you have any idea what that entails? - Yes.
大家都指望着你做钢铁侠  而你却失踪了
People are relying on you to be Iron Man and you've disappeared,
而我只能到处灭你的火
and all I'm doing is putting out your fires
并为此承受压力
and taking the heat for it.
我在尽力做本该你做的工作
I am trying to do the job that you were meant to do.
你是给我拿了草莓来吗
Did you bring me strawberries?
你知道这世上我只对一样东西
Did you know that there's only one thing on Earth
-过敏吗  -草莓过敏
- that I'm allergic to? - Allergic to strawberries.
这是进步  派珀
This is progress, Pepper.
我就知道你跟这玩意有点什么关联
I knew there was a correlation between you and this.
-我需要你  -我也需要你
- I need you... - I need you, too.
-马上离开  -我就是想说这个
- To leave now. - That's what I'm trying to...
波茨小姐
Ms. Potts?
-进来吧  -25分钟后动身
- Come on in. - Wheels up in 25 minutes.
谢谢
Thank you.
还需要什么吗  老板
Anything else, boss?
-不用了  哈皮  -不用  我还需要
- I'm good, Hap. - No, I'll be just...
一小会儿
another minute.
这一离婚俩孩子都不跟我啊
I lost both the kids in the divorce.
不好吗
No.
你在这里还适应吗  娜塔莉
Are you blending in well here, Natalie?
在斯塔克企业
Here at Stark Enterprises?
你是叫娜塔莉  是吧
Your name is Natalie, isn't it?
我以为你俩不和呢
I thought you two didn't get along.
-没有  -你就是不喜欢我啊
- No. That's not so. - It's just me you don't care for.
-不说话吗  -其实  正好你来了
- No? Nothing? - Actually, while you're here,
或许你和娜塔莉可以谈一下
maybe you and Natalie could discuss the
私人物品的事
matter of the personal belongings.
没问题
Absolutely.
你居然能忍住没说
I'm surprised you can keep your mouth shut.
你可真厉害
Boy, you're good.
你的狡猾简直令人赞叹  你怎么做到的
You are mind-blowingly duplicitous. How do you do it?
你就直接破坏...你简直是三重骗子
You just tear things... You're a triple impostor.
我从没见过你这样的
I've never seen anything like you.
你有任何真实的东西吗
Is there anything real about you?
你真会拉丁语吗
Do you even speak Latin?
什么意思  等等  什么
Which means? Wait. What?
你说了什么
What did you just say?
你要么自己开车回家
It means you can either drive yourself home
要么我找人来接你
or I can have you collected.
你真厉害
You're good.
通往未来的钥匙在这里
贾维斯  麻烦你做个数码的结构线框
Jarvis, could you kindly Vac-U-Form a digital wire frame?
我需要可操作的投影
I need a manipulatable projection.
1974年斯塔克博览会模型扫描完成  先生
1974 Stark Expo model scan complete, sir.
一共有多少建筑
How many buildings are there?
要算上比利时华夫饼摊吗
Am I to include the Belgian waffle stands?
你是明知故问  展示出来
That was rhetorical. Just show me.
你觉得那像什么  贾维斯
What does that look like to you, Jarvis?
挺像原子的
Not unlike an atom.
那么原子核就在这里
In which case the nucleus would be here.
高光巨型地球仪
Highlight the unisphere.
删除步道
Lose the footpaths.
删掉
Get rid of them.
您想做什么  先生
What is it you're trying to achieve, sir?
我在发现  纠正
I'm discovering... Correction.
我应该是在重发现一个新元素
I'm rediscovering a new element, I believe.
去掉园艺景观  灌木丛  树什么的
Lose the landscaping, the shrubbery, the trees.
停车场  出口  入口
Parking lots, exits, entrances.
以展馆为框架
Structure the protons and the neutrons
构建质子和中子
using the pavilions as a framework.
爸爸
Dad.
死了近20年
Dead for almost 20 years,
还能教育我
and still taking me to school.
提议的元素应当可以
The proposed element should serve
作为钯的可行替代品
as a viable replacement for palladium.
谢谢  爸爸
Thanks, Dad.
很遗憾  这无法合成
Unfortunately, it is impossible to synthesize.
准备进行大型重装修
Get ready for a major remodel, fellas.
我们又要做硬件了
We're back in hardware mode.
-听说你出过门  -是的
- I heard you broke the perimeter. - Yeah.
那都是三年前了  你去哪了
That was, like, three years ago. Where you been?
-我有事  -我也有  还成功了
- I was doing some stuff. - Yeah, well, me, too, and it worked.
我这是在为主队忙活呢  科尔森
Hey, I'm playing for the home team, Coulson,
为你和你的美毛怪兄弟们忙活
you and all your Fabulous Furry Freak Brothers.
你是要让我工作  还是找我麻烦
Now, are you gonna let me work or break my balls?
这个怎么在这里
What's this doing here?
就是它
That's it.
-拿过来  -你知道这是什么吗
- Bring that to me. - You know what this is?
是我想成功需要的东西
It's exactly what I need to make this work.
把线圈抬起来
Lift the coil.
快点  使劲
Go, go. Put your knees into it.
好了  然后...
There you go. And...
放下吧
Drop it. Drop it.
完全水平  我忙呢  什么事
Perfectly level. I'm busy. What do you want?
没事
Nothing.
再见  我被改派了
Goodbye. I've been reassigned.
弗瑞局长要我去新墨西哥州
Director Fury wants me in New Mexico.
-太棒了  迷人之地  -据说是
- Fantastic. Land of Enchantment. - So I'm told.
-机密事宜吗  -差不多
- Secret stuff? - Something like that.
-祝你好运  -再见
- Good luck. - Bye.
-谢谢  -我们需要你
- Thanks. - We need you.
-是啊  你都想不到  -也没那么需要
- Yeah, more than you know. - Not that much.
启动棱镜加速器
Initializing prismatic accelerator.
正在接近最大能量
Approaching maximum power.
还挺轻松
That was easy.
恭喜  先生
Congratulations, sir.
你创造了新元素
You have created a new element.
先生  反应堆接受了改造能源核
Sir, the reactor has accepted the modified core.
我会开始进行诊断
I will begin running diagnostics.
伊凡
Hey, Ivan.
我跟斯特恩参议员在一起呢
I got Senator Stern here.
我们想过去一趟  看看无人机的设计
Thought we'd swing over and look at some of the drone designs.
无人机还没好呢
The drone is not going to be ready.
没好呢  什么意思
Not ready? What do you mean?
我可以做展示  而不是演示
I can make presentation, not demonstration.
有什么差别
What the hell is the difference?
展示  不飞  不射击
Presentation. No fly. No shoot.
等等
Well, wait, wait. Wait, wait, wait.
那你能让它们做什么
What can you make them do?
这可是武器演示
I mean, this is a weapons demonstration.
-我可以让它们致敬  -致敬
- I can make salute. - You can make salute?
什么意思  "致敬"
What do you mean, "make salute"?
那是什么意思  伊凡
What the hell does that mean, Ivan?
我们说好的可不是这样
This is not what we agreed to, okay?
你先是说能做战衣  然后又说能做无人机
You promised me suits and then you promised me drones.
-一切都会没问题的  -我想要的不是这样
- Hey, man, everything will be okay. - This is not what I wanted.
他在这里呢  鸟人
Hey, there he is. It's the bird man.
你喜欢那只鸟  是吗
Now you like the bird. Is that right?
那是你的鸟吗  我都糊涂了
Is that your bird? I'm confused.
你之前说不是的  但现在看来关系好得很
You said it wasn't, but now it looks like you're best of pals.
你喜欢那只鸟  是吧
You love that bird, don't you?
这样吧  把鸟拿走
You know what? Take the bird.
还有他的枕头  两个都拿走
Take his pillows, too. Both of them.
还有鞋  拿走他的鞋
And his shoes. Take his shoes.
我拿走了你的东西
I took your stuff.
你有什么感觉  难过吗
How does that make you feel? Do you feel bad?
很好  因为那就是我的感觉
Good. 'Cause that's how I feel!
我们有合同的
We had a contract.
我救你一命
I saved your life
你给我战衣
and you give me suits.
那是我们的协议
That was our deal.
而你没能做到
And you did not deliver.
我不知道你是天才还是骗子
I don't know if you're a genius or a fraud.
我不知道你算什么
I don't know what you are.
有很棒的东西恰好从天上掉进了我怀里
Something really, really great fell into my lap.
否则  我今晚只能指望你的本事了
And if it hadn't, I'd be at your mercy tonight.
我自己弄到了一件斯塔克的装置
Now I have a piece of Stark tech that I pimped out myself.
现在  你价格过高的镇纸
And now your overpriced paperweights
会变成我的演示的陪衬
are gonna look like a backdrop to my demonstration.
你明白我想说什么了吧
Do you dig what I'm getting at here?
不知道你是否知道  但我不会说俄语
I don't know if you know this, but I don't speak Russian!
我要走了
I'm gonna leave now.
我要去博览会  或许还能享享艳福
I'm gonna go to the Expo. Maybe I'll even get laid.
看到他们了吗  他们是你的保姆
You see these guys? They're your babysitters.
你最好别惹他们
They are not to be trifled with.
等我回来时  我们要重新商讨
When I get back, we're gonna renegotiate
我们协议的条款
the terms of our agreement.
你要照协议办事
And you're gonna make good on our arrangement
否则
because if you don't,
你会回到我找到你时的状态
you're gonna be exactly what you were when I found you,
做个死人
a dead man.
明白了吗
You got that?
或许你可以在电视上看我
Maybe you can watch me on TV.
呆呆  可以把这里收拾了吗  你真要我命
Dummy, you, can we clean up this mess? You're killing me.
你知道我不...
You know I don't...
屏蔽号码来电  先生
Incoming call with a blocked number, sir.
我的通话权利被恢复了  太好了
My phone privilege is reinstated. Lovely.
科尔森  迷人之地怎么样
Coulson. How's the Land of Enchantment?
托尼  你还好吗
Tony, how you doing?
-我把转速翻倍了  -什么
- I double cycle. - You what?
你说转速翻倍能量会更大  好建议
You told me double cycle's more power. Good advice.
你不是都死了吗  还这么精神
You sound pretty sprightly for a dead guy.
彼此彼此
You, too.
-追踪他  -是
- Trace him. - Sir.
斯塔克之名的真正历史将被书写
Now, the true history of Stark name will be written.
贾维斯  他在哪
Jarvis, where is he?
访问甲骨文网络
Accessing the Oracle grid.
东海岸
Eastern Seaboard.
你父亲40多年前对我家做的事
What your father did to my family over 40 years,
我40分钟后要还给你
I will do to you in 40 minutes.
好啊  我们聚聚  一较高下吧
Sounds good. Let's get together and hash it out.
三州区
Tri-State area.
曼哈顿和外围区
Manhattan and outlying boroughs.
希望你准备好了
I hope you're ready.
通话追踪未完成
Call trace incomplete.
为维护和平
贾斯汀·汉默
-先生  -你要做测试  就做吧
- Sir... - You want to run some tests, run them.
顺便组装战衣  现在就做
And assemble the suit while you're at it. Put it together now.
我们尚不清楚影响...
We are unclear as to the effects...
我不想听  贾维斯
I don't want to hear it, Jarvis.
一股椰子味儿
That tastes like coconut.
还有金属味儿
And metal.
好啊
Yeah!
我会在下面等的
I'll keep the car down here, all right?
谢谢  哈皮
Thank you, Happy.
贾斯汀·汉默
Justin Hammer.
他的展示马上将在主展馆进行
His presentation will begin shortly in the main pavilion.
汉默先进武器系统
好啊
Yeah.
这就对了  谢谢大家前来
That's what I'm talking about. Thanks for coming.
女士们先生们  太久以来
Ladies and gentlemen, for far too long,
这个国家
this country
不得不让它勇敢的儿女身陷险境
has had to place its brave men and women in harm's way,
但后来出现了钢铁侠
but then the Iron Man arrived,
我们以为牺牲生命的日子过去了
and we thought the days of losing lives were behind us.
很遗憾  那项科技我们无法获得
Sadly, that technology was kept out of reach.
那不公平  那不对
That's not fair. That's not right.
-也太可惜了  -天呐
- And it's just too bad. - Oh, Lord.
不管怎样  它还是了不起的创新
Regardless, it was an impressive innovation,
登上了全世界的头条
one that grabbed headlines the world over.
今天  朋友们
Well, today, my friends,
媒体遭遇了一个新问题
the press is faced with quite a different problem.
他们要没墨了
They are about to run out of ink.
拿走
Get that out of here.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
今天我向你们介绍
today I present to you
美国军队的新面孔
the new face of the United States military.
汉默无人机
The Hammer drone.
陆军
Army!
海军
Navy!
空军
Air Force!
陆战队
Marines!
好啊
Yeah!
真棒
要我说  这可比拉拉队好多了
That's a hell of a lot better than some cheerleaders, let me tell you.
但这项技术虽然极具革命性
But as revolutionary as this technology is,
总还是会有
there will always be a need
需要人亲临战场的时候
for man to be present in the theater of war.
女士们先生们  今天我骄傲地向大家介绍
Ladies and gentlemen, today I am proud to present to you
原型机1号
the very first prototype in
多威胁响应战衣
the Variable Threat Response Battle Suit
及其驾驶员  空军中校詹姆斯·罗德
and its pilot, Air Force Lieutenant Colonel James Rhodes.
什么
What?
对于美国和其盟友  汉默工业将...
For America and its allies, Hammer Industries is reporting for...
我们有麻烦了
We got trouble.
托尼  现场还有平民呢
Tony, there are civilians present.
我是受命前来  咱们现在别闹
I'm here on orders. Let's not do this right now.
冲大家挥挥手
Give them a wave.
好啊  好
Hey, all right. Yeah.
他们都有危险  我们得让他们撤离
All these people are in danger. We gotta get them out of here.
你接下来五分钟里得相信我
You gotta trust me for the next five minutes.
我试过了  结果在你家被丢来丢去
Yeah, I tried that. I got tossed around your house,
-记得吗  -听我说  我认为他在跟万科合作
- remember? - Listen, I think he's working with Vanko.
万科还活着
Vanko's alive?
好啊
Yeah.
他在哪
Where is he?
-什么  -万科在哪
- What? - Where's Vanko?
-谁  -说
- Who? - Tell me.
你为什么要来啊
What are you doing here, man?
启动
-是你弄的吗  -不是  不是我
- Is that you? - No, I'm not doing that.
不是我启动的
That's not me.
我动不了了  我被锁定了  我被锁定了
I can't move. I'm locked up. I'm locked up!
快走  整个系统都被入侵了
Get out of here. Go! This whole system's been compromised.
我们出去打
Let's take it outside.
启用
不  不
No. No!
贾维斯  黑进去
Jarvis, break in.
-我得控制他  -是  先生
- I need to own him. - Yes, sir.
托尼  我锁定了  我锁定目标了
Tony, Tony, I'm locked on. I have target lock.
-锁定什么  -你
- On what? - On you.
托尼  你后面
Tony, on your six!
怎么回事  发生了什么事
What's going on? What's happening?
软件被覆盖了
The software's been overridden.
什么  什么叫被覆盖了
What? What do you mean it's been overridden?
-那什么意思  -他应该是控制了无人机
- What does that mean? - I think he slaved the drones.
那不可能
That's impossible.
-联系守卫  -电话都断线了  先生
- Call the guards. - All the phones are down, sir.
那打手机
Well, then call their... Call their cells.
手机也打不通  先生
Their cell phones are not working, either, sir.
他把我们锁在主机外面了
He's locked us out of the mainframe.
谁把你锁在主机外面了
Who's locked you out of the mainframe?
拜托  走开吧
Please, please, go away. Go away.
-我能处理好  -是吗
- I've got this handled. - Have you now?
是的
Yes, I do.
事实上  要不是你那位来了
In fact, if your guy hadn't showed up,
也不会出这种事
this wouldn't be happening.
拜托了  走吧  谢谢
So please, now go away. Thank you.
我们得把这俩小妞赶出去
Listen, we got to get these bitches out of here.
什么
What?
告诉我是谁搞的鬼
You tell me who's behind this.
是谁搞的鬼
Who's behind this?
伊凡  伊凡·万科
Ivan. Ivan Vanko.
-他在哪  -在我的公司
- Where is he? - He's at my facility.
-请接纽约警局  -不不
- I need NYPD, please. - No, no, no!
-指挥中心  -不  甜心
- Command Central. - No, no, honey.
-别联系当局  -好  马上
- Don't call the authorities. - Okay. Right away. Right away.
让开  让开
Step aside. Step aside.
把你知道的情况都告诉我  说
Tell me everything you know. Go.
-怎么样了  贾维斯  -远程重启失败
- How are we doing, Jarvis? - Remote reboot unsuccessful.
这边来
This way.
没人接电话  怎么回事啊
Nobody's answering the phone. What's going on?
上车  带我去汉默工业
Get in the car. Take me to Hammer Industries.
我不会带你去任何地方的
I'm not taking you anywhere.
好啊  你要我来开车吗
Fine. You want me to drive?
不  我开车  上车
No, I'm driving. Get in the car.
下线
好样的  孩子
Nice work, kid.
多个敌人靠近你了
You got multiples coming in on you.
把火力从博览会引开吧
Let's get this away from the Expo.
等我们到了  我需要你守在外面
When we arrive, I need you to watch the perimeter.
我要进入大楼  拿下目标
I'm gonna enter the facility and take down the target.
-看路  -没问题
- Watch the road. - I got it. I got it.
下线
听着
Listen, listen.
有一群刚离队  又调头回博览会了
A pack just peeled off. They're headed back to the Expo.
好
Got it.
我靠近你了
I'm closing on you.
大炮准备发射了  托尼  小心
Ordnance coming in hot, Tony. Watch it.
-留在车里  -我不要留在车里
- Stay in the car. - I'm not staying in the car.
我叫你留在车里了
I said, stay in the car.
你穿的是什么
What are you wearing?
我不会让你一个人进去的
Look, I'm not letting you go in there alone.
你想帮忙吗  车别熄火
You want to help? Keep the car running.
好
Okay.
安全漏洞
你不能进来
You can't come in here.
等等
Hold on.
启用
每一组无人机都在用
Each set of drones is communicating
独特的语言沟通
in its own unique language.
那就选一个  只用那个
Well, choose one and focus on that.
你试过俄语吗  试试俄语吧
Have you tried Russian? Why don't you try Russian?
注意  W区有闯入者
Attention. We have intrusion on Grid W.
收到  就去
We got it. We're on our way.
我打倒他了
I got him!
-罗德  你还锁定着呢吗  -是啊
- Rhodey, you still locked on? - Yeah.
是恶搞了一句军队俗语
丢下袜子  抓条鳄鱼
Drop your socks and grab your Crocs.
我们要湿了脚了
We're about to get wet on this ride.
等等
Wait, wait, wait!
他跑了
He's gone.
抱歉  哥们  必须甩掉几个
I'm sorry, buddy. Had to thin out the herd.
你的位置
What's your 20?
-你在干什么  -重启罗德的战衣
- What are you doing? - I'm rebooting Rhodey's suit.
托尼
Tony!
访问系统
重启完成
Reboot complete.
你的铁哥们回来了
You got your best friend back.
非常感谢  罗曼诺夫特工
Thank you very much, Agent Romanoff.
新胸膛电源做得好
Well done with the new chest piece.
我看到输出显著提高
I am reading significantly higher output
你的生命体征看上去也好多了
and your vitals all look promising.
是啊  我暂时不会死了  谢谢
Yes, for the moment, I'm not dying. Thank you.
什么叫你不会死了  你是说你要死了吗
What do you mean you're not dying? Did you just say you're dying?
那是你吗  我不会死的
Is that you? No, I'm not.
-现在不会了  -怎么回事啊
- Not anymore. - What's going on?
我本打算告诉你的  我不想吓到你
I was going to tell you. I didn't want to alarm you.
你本打算告诉我的  你原本真要死了吗
You were gonna tell me? You really were dying?
-你没让我说出口  -你怎么不告诉我
- You didn't let me. - Why didn't you tell me that?
我本想给你做个煎蛋卷顺便告诉你的
I was gonna make you an omelet and tell you.
蜜月再吵  有敌人来了  托尼
Save it for the honeymoon. You got incoming, Tony.
看来他们都去找你了
Looks like the fight's coming to you.
-好  派珀  -你现在没事了吧
- Great. Pepper? - Are you okay now?
我没事了  别生气
I am fine. Don't be mad.
-我会正式道歉的  -我就生气了
- I will formally apologize... - I am mad!
等我不用抵御汉默无人机攻击了的
When I'm not fending off a Hammeroid attack.
-好吧  -我们本可以去威尼斯的
- Fine. - We could have been in Venice.
得了
Oh, please.
罗德
Rhodes?
醒醒  哥们  我需要你
Snap out of it, buddy. I need you.
他们来了  快点  起来
They're coming. Come on, let's roll. Get up.
天呐  这战衣还你好了
Oh, man. You can have your suit back.
你没事吧
You Okay?
嗯  谢谢
Yeah, thanks.
-托尼  对不起  -不用
- Tony, look, I'm sorry, okay? - Don't be.
不  我本该更信任你的
No. I should have trusted you more.
是我害你陷入了这样的局面  别想了
I'm the one who put you in this position. Forget it.
不  的确怪你  但我想说句对不起
No. It's your fault. I just wanted to say I'm sorry.
谢谢  我就想听到这个  搭档
Thank you. That's all I wanted to hear. Partner.
他们随时会火力全开地冲过来  有什么计划
They're coming in hot, any second. What's the play?
我们得占领高地
Well, we want to take the high ground, okay?
把火力最大的武器安排在山脊上
So let's put the biggest gun up on that ridge.
好的
Got you.
-你想站哪  -你去哪
- Where do you want to be? - Where are you going?
你说什么呢
What're you talking about?
-我是指我啦  -你有件重武器
- I meant me. - You have a big gun.
但你不是重武器
You are not the big gun.
-托尼  别嫉妒嘛  -不  真低调
- Tony, don't be jealous. - No. It's subtle,
-这么多花里胡哨  -嗯
- all the bells and whistles. - Yeah.
-这叫狠角色  -好吧
- It's called being a badass. - Fine.
好吧  你上去  我引他们过来
All right. You go up top. I'll draw them in.
别待在这下面  这位置最糟了
Don't stay down here. This is the worst place to be.
好吧  你有位置了
Okay, you got a spot.
-那我站哪  -这叫死地  托尼
- Where's mine? - It's the kill box, Tony. Okay?
你会死在这里的
This is where you go to die.
-看到了吗  -嗯  厉害
- See that? - Yeah, yeah, nice.
罗德
Rhodey'?
蹲下
Get down.
下次你该先用那个
I think you should lead with that next time.
嗯  抱歉  老大
Yeah. Sorry, boss.
这个我只能用一次  一次性的
I can only use it once. It's a one-off.
我五分钟前就说了
I told you that five minutes ago.
就是他
That's your guy here.
-什么  -你被捕了
- Excuse me? - You're being placed under arrest.
-开什么玩笑  -手背后  先生
- Are you kidding me? - Hands behind your back, sir.
我在帮忙呢
I'm trying to help here.
我懂了  我明白你想干什么了
I get it. I see what you're doing.
你想扣在我头上  是吗
You're trying to pin this on me, huh?
好啊  厉害
That's good. That's good.
你开始有执行总裁的样子了  铲除对手
You're starting to think like a CEO, taking out the competition.
我喜欢  你以为你搞倒我了吗
I like that. You think you're making a problem for me?
我会给你制造麻烦的
I'm gonna make a problem for you.
我们很快会再见的
I'm gonna be seeing you again real soon.
等他们到了  最好把他们安排在
When they get here, I think you should station them
南侧  东侧和两个西侧出口
at the south, east and both west exits.
我们已经关闭了进出威利点的7号列车
We shut down the 7 train in and out of Willets Point already.
让城际大巴送民众去运行线路疏散
Well, have city buses there to ferry people to operating lines.
好  你跟我们来吗
Yeah. Are you coming with us?
-不  我要待在这儿  等园区清空  -好
- No, I'm gonna stay till the park is clear. - Okay.
注意  又飞来一个无人机
Heads up. You got one more drone incoming.
这个看上去不一样
This one looks different.
冲击能量高得多
The repulsor signature is significantly higher.
很高兴又碰面了
Good to be back.
这可不妙
This ain't gonna be good.
我为这家伙准备了特别的东西
I got something special for this guy.
我要用前妻炸开他的堡垒
I'm gonna bust his bunker with the Ex-Wife.
什么
With the what?
汉默科技吗
Hammer tech?
是啊
Yeah.
交给我吧
I got this.
罗德  我有主意了
Rhodes. I got an idea.
-你想当英雄吗  -什么
- You want to be a hero? - What?
我需要个跟班  把手举起来
I could really use a sidekick. Put your hand up.
-这就是你的主意  -嗯
- This is your idea? - Yep.
我准备好了  开始吧
I'm ready. I'm ready. Go, go, go!
接招
Take it.
你输了
You lose.
这些无人机都要爆炸了
All these drones are rigged to blow.
我们得赶紧走  哥们
We gotta get out of here, man.
派珀
Pepper?
天呐  我真受不了了
Oh, my God! I can't take this anymore.
-你受不了了  -我受不了了
- You can't? - I can't take this.
-看看我啊  -我的身体
- Look at me. - My body, literally,
真是受不了这压力了
cannot handle the stress.
我都无法知道你是会
I never know if you're gonna
害死自己  还是祸害整个公司
kill yourself or wreck the whole company.
我觉得我干得还挺不错的
I think I did okay.
我辞职  我要辞职
I quit. I'm resigning.
我受够了
That's it.
你说什么  你不干了
What did you just say? You're done?
真是意外  也不意外
That's surprising. No, it's not surprising.
我懂的
I get it.
你不用找借口
You don't have to make any excuses.
我没想找借口
I'm... I'm... I'm not making any excuses.
你其实刚刚就找了借口
You actually were just making excuses.
-但不用的  -不  那不是找借口
- But you don't have to. - No, I wasn't making an excuse.
-听我说  -我很有道理的
- Listen. - I'm actually very justified.
-你应当得到更好的  -是啊
- You deserve better. - Well...
你一直把我照顾得那么好
You've taken such good care of me.
我本来很辛苦  但你帮我撑了过来
I've been in a tough spot, but you got me through it, so...
是吧
Right?
-谢谢  -嗯
- Thank you. - Yeah.
-谢谢你的理解  -我们谈谈后续吧
- Thank you for understanding. - Yeah, yeah. Let's talk clean-up.
我会处理好过度
I'll handle the transition.
-会很顺利的  -好  那媒体呢
- It'll be smooth. - Okay. What about the press?
你才干了一周  这看上去会...
Because you only had the job for a week. That's gonna seem...
-给你干简直度日如年  -我知道
- Well, with you it's like dog years. - I know.
就像做总统
I mean, it's like the Presidency...
奇怪
Weird.
-不  不奇怪  -还好  是吧
- No, it's not weird. - It's okay, right?
-嗯  -再来一次
- Yeah. - Run that by me again.
我觉得挺奇怪的
I think it was weird.
你俩像抢夺葡萄的两只海豹
You guys look like two seals fighting over a grape.
-我刚辞职了  -所以我们不...
- I had just quit, actually. - Yeah, so we're not...
你们不用解释  我都听到了
You don't have to do that. I heard the whole thing.
你该滚蛋
You should get lost.
我先到的  自己去找个屋顶啦
I was here first. Get a roof.
我以为你没有俏皮话可讲了呢
I thought you were out of one-liners.
这是最后一句
That's the last one.
你刚刚表现得很厉害
You kicked ass back there, by the way.
谢谢  你也是
Thank you. You, too.
听着  我的车被爆炸炸毁了
Listen, my car got taken out in the explosion,
我得多用会儿你的战衣  好吗
so I'm gonna have to hang on to your suit for a minute, okay?
不行  不能接受
Not okay. Not okay with that.
不是在问你
It wasn't a question.
如果我不接受  你要怎么辞职
How are you gonna resign if I don't accept?
复仇者联盟
初步报告
我可不希望你看那个
I don't think I want you looking at that.
我不确定这是否还跟你有关
I'm not sure it pertains to you anymore.
这个嘛
Now this, on the other hand,
是罗曼诺夫特工对你的评估
is Agent Romanoff's assessment of you.
读读吧
Read it.
个性概述  斯塔克先生表现出了强迫性行为
"Personality overview. Mr. Stark displays compulsive behavior."
我得说一句  那是上周了
In my own defense, that was last week.
有自毁倾向  我当时要死了啊
"Prone to self-destructive tendencies." I was dying.
拜托  再说  我们不都有点吗
I mean, please. And aren't we all?
标准自恋狂
"Textbook narcissism"?
没说错
Agreed.
好吧  到了
Okay, here it is.
复仇者联盟招募评估  钢铁侠  可以
"Recruitment assessment for Avenger Initiative. Iron Man? Yes."
-我得考虑一下  -继续读
- I gotta think about it. - Read on.
托尼·斯塔克不...
"Tony Stark not...
不推荐
"Not recommended"?
这没道理
That doesn't make any sense.
怎么又认可我又不认可我
How can you approve me but not approve me?
我有新心脏了
I got a new ticker.
我想好好对派珀
I'm trying to do right by Pepper.
我在谈还算稳定的恋爱
I'm in a stable-ish relationship.
因此我们认为  目前
Which leads us to believe at this juncture
我们最好只请你做顾问
we'd only like to use you as a consultant.
你请不起我
You can't afford me.
不过  我愿放弃我的固定预付聘金
Then again, I will waive my customary retainer
以求你帮个小忙
in exchange for a small favor.
罗德和我要去华盛顿
Rhodey and I are being honored
接受表彰  我们需要个颁奖人
in Washington and we need a presenter.
我会想办法的
I'll see what I can do.
今天  我很荣幸能在这里
It is my honor to be here today
将这份荣誉
to present these distinguished awards
颁给詹姆斯·罗德中校和托尼·斯塔克先生
to Lieutenant Colonel James Rhodes and Mr. Tony Stark,
他是国宝级人物
who is, of course, a national treasure.
谢谢  中校
Thank you, Lieutenant Colonel,
感谢你杰出的表现
for such an exceptionally distinguished performance.
-这是你应得的  -谢谢  先生
- You deserve this. - Thank you, sir.
斯塔克先生
Mr. Stark.
感谢你杰出的表现
Thank you for such an exceptionally distinguished performance.
这是你应得的
You deserve this.
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
一个小刺[混蛋]居然能这么讨人厌  是吧
Funny how annoying a little prick can be, isn't it?
拍张照吧
Let's get a photo.
美国新墨西哥州
迷人之地
长官  我们找到了
Sir, we've found it.